<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>impedance | Pablo Bernabeu</title>
    <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/impedance/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/impedance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>impedance</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Pablo Bernabeu, 2015—2024. Licence: [CC BY 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/). Email: pcbernabeu@gmail.com. No cookies operated by this website. Cookies only used by third-party systems such as [Disqus](https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717155-use-of-cookies).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/img/default_preview_image.png</url>
      <title>impedance</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/impedance/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the impedance in electroencephalography using a blunt needle, electrolyte gel and wiggling</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2024/lowering-impedance-in-electroencephalography-using-a-blunt-needle-electrolyte-gel-and-wiggling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2024/lowering-impedance-in-electroencephalography-using-a-blunt-needle-electrolyte-gel-and-wiggling/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Reducing the impedance in electroencephalography (EEG) is crucial for capturing high-quality brain activity signals. This process involves ensuring that electrodes make optimal contact with the skin without harming the participant. Below are a few tips to achieve this using a blunt needle, electrolyte gel and gentle wiggling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;first-do-no-harm&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First, Do No Harm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary goal is to reduce the impedance without damaging the skin or causing discomfort. Only use disposable, blunt needles, and never let the needle pierce the skin. While wiggling the needle under each electrode, do not any apply any force down on the skin. To achieve this, hold the syringe with the minimum grip force needed to keep under control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;manage-the-angle-of-the-needle&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Manage the Angle of the Needle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The needle should be positioned at an angle of around 20–50 degrees relative to the participant’s skin. To attain such an angle, electrodes may be rotated, and the researcher may adjust their own position around the participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;manage-the-depth-of-the-needle&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Manage the Depth of the Needle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be cautious about the depth of the needle. The goal is to make contact with the skin but not scratch it. Gently wiggle the needle to maximize electrode contact with the skin, which helps lower the impedance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-top: 56.25%; margin-top: 7%;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4KLtp-WnOOo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen
      style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;apply-gel-strategically&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apply Gel Strategically&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use just enough electrolyte gel to reduce the impedance, but avoid creating bridges between adjacent electrodes. A small amount of gel should be visible on the opening of each electrode, and any large lumps should be carefully removed. This ensures that each electrode maintains a distinct connection with the skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;control-the-swing-of-the-electrode&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Control the Swing of the Electrode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place your finger on the electrode throughout the wiggling to feel and control its movement. This helps prevent excess gel from forming a bump under the electrode, which could lead to inaccurate readings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;wiggle-with-precision&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wiggle with Precision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Position yourself comfortably to work on each electrode, allowing for precise movements and minimising participant discomfort. Wiggle the needle in small circular motions to move hair aside and ensure good skin contact. Be careful not to scratch the skin in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By following these tips, you’ll achieve lower impedance without causing harm, ensuring high-quality EEG data and a better experience for the participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
