<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brain Vision | Pablo Bernabeu</title>
    <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/brain-vision/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/brain-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Brain Vision</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Pablo Bernabeu, 2015—2026. Licence: [CC BY 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/). Email: pcbernabeu@gmail.com. Cookies only used by third-party systems such as [Disqus](https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717155-use-of-cookies).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/img/default_preview_image.png</url>
      <title>Brain Vision</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/brain-vision/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-related potentials: Why and how I used them</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2020/event-related-potentials-why-and-how-i-used-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2020/event-related-potentials-why-and-how-i-used-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Event-related potentials (ERPs) offer a unique insight in the study of human cognition. Let&#39;s look at their reason-to-be for the purposes of research, and how they are defined and processed. Most of this content is based on my master&#39;s thesis, which I could fortunately conduct at the Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics (see &lt;a href=&#39;https://psyarxiv.com/5gjvk/&#39;&gt;thesis&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#39;https://psyarxiv.com/a5pcz/&#39;&gt;conference paper&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;electroencephalography&#34;&gt;Electroencephalography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brain produces electrical activity all the time, which can be measured via electrodes on the scalp—a method known as electroencephalography (EEG). These pulses are produced for every one of our states and actions, in a voltage at a micro (µ) scale, typically between 10 µV (0.000010) and 100 µV (0.000100; Aurlien et al., 2004). The overlapping pulses happen at extremely high frequencies; indeed, the signal can be measured once per millisecond. The high frequency of this signal is very interesting for the study of some cognitive processes in particular, for which the time course is (or may be) critical. One such example is conceptual processing, namely, the process of understanding the meaning of words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research has revealed the relation between certain EEG patterns and cognitive states and functions. Brain activity includes dozens of types, but broadly, it can be divided into neural oscillations and event-related potentials. Specific oscillations (also known as brain waves) are associated with &lt;em&gt;states&lt;/em&gt; such as wakefulness, sleep, arousal, relaxation, etc. (Roohi-Azizi et al., 2017). Event-related potentials instead represent more finite &lt;em&gt;events&lt;/em&gt;, such as the presentation of as a stimulus. In cognitive neuroscience, both oscillations and ERPs are studied, whereas in cognitive psychology, ERPs are much more common than oscillations. Let&#39;s dive into ERPs below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;event-related-potentials&#34;&gt;Event-related potentials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the lab, ERPs are elicited using controlled designs. In each trial, a series of stimuli are presented. At a fixed point therein, an EEG measurement begins and spans for a certain period. In turn, in the analysis, this measurement period is divided into &lt;em&gt;time windows&lt;/em&gt;, which often correspond to specific ERP components (e.g., N400 window).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In psycholinguistics, for instance, a typical scenario is the presentation of words, and ERPs are systematically &lt;em&gt;time-locked&lt;/em&gt; to the same position in consecutive trials, often the onset of a word. By this means, the experimental manipulation is collected, and the non-experimental variation—&amp;lsquo;noise&amp;rsquo;—is largely cancelled out by the aggregation of multiple trials that share the experimental manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chief reason to employ the ERP method is the measurement of cognitive processes online, that is, precisely as they unfold. This is fitting in the context of language comprehension, where some important processes last for less than a second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-course-of-word-processing&#34;&gt;Time course of word processing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processing a word takes around 800 milliseconds (ms). Within that time, earlier processes (compared to later ones) have been ascribed greater relevance to the core process of understanding a word (Mahon &amp;amp; Caramazza, 2008). This assumes that broader processes start only after more immediate ones have started (but see Lebois, Wilson‐Mendenhall &amp;amp; Barsalou, 2014). The most immediate process is the recognition of a string of letters, which seems to start within 90 ms post word onset in early auditory cortex and the Visual Word Form Area (Willems et al., 2016). Then ensue further, fundamental stages known as &lt;em&gt;lexical&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;semantic&lt;/em&gt; processes. Lexical processing is the identification of a string of letters as a known word, and it happens within around 160 ms post word onset. Next, at around 200 ms, we may see the beginning of semantic processing, which denotes a further step in the cognitive analysis of the word that is akin to &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; (Hauk, 2016). These processes may overlap, as indeed suggested by the sensitivity of the N400 ERP (see also next section) to both lexical and semantic tasks (Kutas &amp;amp; Federmeier, 2011). Both processes also likely extend further in the processing timeline (Hauk, 2016). In spite of this overlap, however, lexical and semantic processing have often been linked to different cognitive phenomena. For instance, tasks promoting semantic processing (e.g., semantic decision, whereby participants describe words as concrete or abstract) have been found to engage sensorimotor simulation of the word&#39;s meaning (known as &lt;em&gt;embodiment&lt;/em&gt;) more strongly than lexical tasks do (Connell &amp;amp; Lynott, 2013; Pexman et al., 2019; Sato et al., 2008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the lexical and semantic stages have emerged, post-lexical, post-semantic processes follow (Mahon &amp;amp; Caramazza, 2008). These are mental imagery and episodic memory processes—both with an approximate emergence around 270 ms after word onset. The gradual progression from the identification of a word up to accessing its broadest meaning is an important anchoring point in the current research on the alleged embodiment of meaning comprehension, even if we might hope to count on more definitive threshold points (Hauk, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word processing data are mainly based on written word processing, but spoken words are processed quite similarly, if slightly faster (Leonard et al., 2016; Pulvermüller et al., 2005; Shtyrov et al., 2004).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bigger take-home messages would be: (1) the processing of meaning might only start at around 160 ms post word onset, and (2) processes outside of meaning comprehension might only start at around 270 ms. These working references must be taken with some caution because particular semantic effects have been found at different stages (e.g., the conceptual modality switch, as in Hald et al., 2011; Collins, Pecher et al., 2011). Indeed, in an influential critique of blooming findings on embodiment, Mahon and Caramazza (2008) argued that even early effects might possibly be explained in terms of non-embodied processing. They contended that working memory processes that were ancillary rather than semantic could be quickly engaged with the function of ‘colouring’ a concept, not building it up. To further complicate the matter, we do not have absolute certainty on the later section of the time course. Thus, as Hauk (2016) reviews, the different stages likely overlap at certain points, with different degrees of relevance. For instance, lexical processing may continue even once semantic processing has started, but would naturally become less relevant. Indeed, the relation among these processes is likely more of a continuum than a set of clear-cut modules. In a nutshell, the time course is important with some experimental effects in word processing, and, to that extent, we depend on our knowledge of the basic time course of word processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-conceptual-modality-switch-paradigm-and-its-time-course&#34;&gt;The conceptual modality switch paradigm and its time course&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In demonstrating the relevance of embodied cognition, a sizeable series of studies have shown that reading about different conceptual modalities (e.g., auditory ‘loud bell’ followed by visual ‘pink background’) incurs processing costs (Pecher et al., 2003). Importantly, this manipulation does not concern the presentation mode of the stimulus, maintained constant, but the intrinsic semantic modality of the stimulus concepts. The conceptual modality switch effect has often been replicated (Pecher et al., 2004; Solomon &amp;amp; Barsalou, 2004; Marques, 2006; Vermeulen et al., 2007; van Dantzig et al., 2008; Lynott &amp;amp; Connell, 2009; Ambrosi et al., 2011; Collins et al., 2011; Hald et al., 2011; Hald et al., 2013; Scerrati et al., 2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, Willems and Louwerse (2017) addressed a caveat with the time course of the conceptual modality switch paradigm. In previous experiments, trials presented a concept word followed by a property word. ERPs were time-locked to the latter property word. This design may have left uncontrolled a switch produced already at the concept. Indeed, the property word was already supposed to be in the particular modality of the trial. That pitfall could have had two consequences: loss of power and loss of certainty on the time course of the effect. Thus, Bernabeu et al. created a design in which ERPs were time-locked to the first word in target trials (see some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/post/Conceptual_modality_switch_effect_measured_at_first_word&#34;&gt;early input from researchers online&lt;/a&gt;). The purpose of this relocation was not to completely annul the possibility of post-core sensory processes, but to increase the time accuracy by measuring the modality switch from the point at which it is elicited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;designoverview.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing this design had an ancillary effect on the measurement of response times. A psycholinguistic experiment like this one requires controlling fundamental variables such as word frequency and length, by matching the means of these variables across experimental conditions. This must be controlled in the target words at least. As it is often the case, this control was only possible in the target words—the first one in target trials—, but it was not possible in the second word, which is the crucial one for response times. Response times could still be measured, but comparisons across conditions were not fully warranted. In sum, this was an ERP design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;erp-components&#34;&gt;ERP components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the ERP signal is plotted, it displays multiple wave shapes, or &lt;em&gt;waveforms&lt;/em&gt;, each with a peak flanked by falling tails. Each of these waves often corresponds to an ERP component, which is what cognitive scientists are often interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple components are known, each having been found to consistently peak around specific points in time during a cognitive process. The peak is one of several features characterising each component. A sketch list is shown below (van Hell &amp;amp; Kroll, 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polarity:&lt;/strong&gt; The component either peaks in the positive or the negative pole of the signal. This polarity is relative to the &lt;em&gt;baseline&lt;/em&gt; point that is created in the preprocessing stage (see below);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latency:&lt;/strong&gt; the time course of the component, encompassing an onset, a peak and an overall duration. Time windows are normally set to match relevant components (e.g., the N400 window, etc.);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amplitude:&lt;/strong&gt; the voltage reached at a given time (e.g., the peak) or for a certain period (e.g., a time window);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalp distribution, or topography:&lt;/strong&gt; the areas on the scalp (the scalp being a reasonable proxy for the brain) in which the component appears;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Functional role:&lt;/strong&gt; the cognitive functions that have been consistently associated with the component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of components in language processing include the N400, consistently linked to semantic processing, that is, seeking the meaning of words or sentences. The N400 is characterised by a large, negative amplitude peaking at around 400 ms post word onset, primarily found in central and posterior sites. N400 &lt;em&gt;effects&lt;/em&gt;, which are comparisons of the N400 component in different experimental conditions, have consistently appeared under violations of semantic expectations, i.e., related to meaning and events (Kutas &amp;amp; Federmeier, 2011; Swaab et al., 2012). Another well-known component in language is the P600, linked to syntactic processing, which allows the comprehension of sentences (Swaab et al., 2012). Other examples of components include lateralized readiness potentials, signalling motor preparation (Mordkoff &amp;amp; Gianaros, 2000), and the P3b component, which appears in the context of responses (van Vliet et al., 2014). Both of the latter components are relevant to researchers across domains, who often need to ward off &lt;em&gt;contamination&lt;/em&gt; from these components in their experiments. In Bernabeu et al.&amp;lsquo;s experiment, for instance, part of the reason why ERPs were time-locked to the first word in target trials was to prevent contamination from these components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERP data sets are large, being the product of the number of electrodes (also called &amp;lsquo;channels&amp;rsquo;) times the number of time points, times the number of experimental conditions, and times the number of participants. In recent studies, the number of trials often adds to that product, whereas in previous experiments, the trials tended to be aggregated in each condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eeg-montage&#34;&gt;EEG montage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EEG montage is an important factor. The options are broadly characterised by three parameters of the electrodes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 30px; line-height: 1.2; padding-bottom: 12px; padding-left: 15px; float: right; display: block;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;EEG MPI open day photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pablo Bernabeu, 2015&#34; width=&#34;170px&#34; style=&#39;padding-bottom: 15px; margin-bottom: 0px;&#39; /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: small; padding-left: 5px; padding-top: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;Brainwaves exposed at an open day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active / passive:&lt;/strong&gt; Active electrodes amplify the EEG signal directly at the scalp, whereas passive electrodes require the raw signal to be sent through a lead (i.e., a wire) and up to an amplifier. In the latter case, the lead acts as an antenna, picking up ambient electrical noise. This noise can hinder the subtle measurement of interest. This problem is solved by active electrodes (Laszlo et al., 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number:&lt;/strong&gt; Traditionally, montages with 32, 64 or 128 electrodes have been used. The more electrodes, the &amp;lsquo;denser&amp;rsquo; the montage, and the higher the spatial resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wet / dry:&lt;/strong&gt; In some montages, the electrical conductance on the electrodes&amp;rsquo; contact point must be increased using some fluid solutions, such as a specific gel (often commercialised by the companies that also make EEG apparatuses). Conversely, other electrodes function in a dry way. Ensuring the proper conductance on wet electrodes has traditionally been very time-consuming for experimenters, often taking over half an hour of wiggling a blunt syringe distributing the saline solution around the tip. Traditionally, wet electrodes produced more reliable data than dry ones, but &lt;em&gt;the times they are a&#39;changing&lt;/em&gt; (di Flumeri, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An EEG/ERP experiment is time-consuming. The preparation (especially conductance-prompting with wet montages) and post-experiment procedures (especially washing the EEG cap) often take four or five times as long as the experiment proper. These procedures are especially long for higher-density, wet montages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preprocessing-erps&#34;&gt;Preprocessing ERPs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERPs are not the first signal collected in experiments. They are obtained after considerable, systematic preprocessing of the EEG signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.researchgate.net/post/EEG_error_datasets_missing_channels_Its_strange_because_they_were_recorded_well_and_faulty_files_are_quite_as_heavy_as_the_good_ones_Any_ideas&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Nikolay_Novitskiy/post/EEG_error_datasets_missing_channels_Its_strange_because_they_were_recorded_well_and_faulty_files_are_quite_as_heavy_as_the_good_ones_Any_ideas/attachment/59d6391b79197b8077996520/AS%3A400433085468672%401472482095219/image/41_64ch.png&#34; alt=&#34;Brain Vision waveforms&#34; width=&#39;70%&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bernabeu et al. (2017), I used Brain Vision software, and followed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://erpinfo.org/resources&#34;&gt;tutorials from the well-known ERP Boot Camp&lt;/a&gt; of Steve Luck and Emily Kappenman. I applied the following pipeline for each participant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;labeling channels (64 electrodes);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;creating channel groups (anterior and posterior);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;re-referencing the signal offline to the right mastoid (RM), having referenced online to the left mastoid (Ref);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;EEG montage.png&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;separating my three experimental conditions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ocular correction for blinks and significant, vertical or horizontal movements of the eyes (seminal method by Gratton et al., 1983, which is the default in Brain Vision);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;baseline correction, which is a standardisation based on a certain period immediately before the onset of the target manipulation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;further correction of artifacts such as motor action potentials (or lateralised readiness potentials) resulting from even the subtlest muscle activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pipeline is reflected in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/98fs6/&#34;&gt;scripts exported from Brain Vision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &amp;lt;Nodes&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch/OcularCorrection&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif/minave_TotalMatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch/OcularCorrection&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif/minave_EmbodiedMismatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch/OcularCorrection&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif/minave_TotalMismatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/Nodes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word reading ERPs can look somewhat like this after the preprocessing (&lt;a href=&#39;https://osf.io/bz7ae/&#39;&gt;plots made in R&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;Four main waveform plots stacked.png&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To visualise these waveforms throughout the different sections of the data, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pablobernabeu.shinyapps.io/ERP-waveform-visualization_CMS-experiment&#34;&gt;dashboard is available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statistical-analysis&#34;&gt;Statistical analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the myriad repeated measures involved in EEG, linear mixed-effects models are a good option, allowing the registration of electrodes and time points in the error term per participant (and trial, too, if these are not aggregated). The statistical analysis is &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/sx3nw&#34;&gt;available on OSF&lt;/a&gt; (to view the plots, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/download/sx3nw&#34;&gt;download the document&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://mfr.osf.io/render?url=https%3A%2F%2Fosf.io%2Fdownload%2Fsx3nw%2F%3Fdirect%26mode%3Drender&#34;
        width=&#34;100%&#34;
        scrolling=&#34;yes&#34;
        height=&#34;677px&#34;
        marginheight=&#34;0&#34;
        frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
        allowfullscreen
        webkitallowfullscreen
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event-related potentials fulfil an important role in cognitive neuroscience and psychology, only surpassed by magnetic electroencephalography (MEG), which unites high temporal and spatial resolution. Learning how to use ERPs is demanding but even more rewarding. It certainly does not make for fast science, but allows the measurement of experimental effects online, that is, as they unfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn about and overcome multiple challenges. One of the issues I faced once regarded some channels (electrodes) that appeared to be missing from the data. I posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/post/EEG_error_datasets_missing_channels_Its_strange_because_they_were_recorded_well_and_faulty_files_are_quite_as_heavy_as_the_good_ones_Any_ideas&#34;&gt;question on ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt;, and emailed Brain Products, the maker of Brain Vision Recorder, which I was using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could please give me a hand with this error, I would be very grateful. I have EEG from a psychological experiment, recorded with BrainVision Recorder, and being analyzed with BrainVision Analyzer 2. Most of the recordings are perfectly fine, but a few present a big error. Out of 64 original electrodes, only two appear. These are the right mastoid (RM) and the left eye sensor (LEOG). Both are bipolar electrodes. RM is to be re-referenced to the online reference electrode, while LEOG is to be re-referenced to the right eye electrode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just can&#39;t fathom the error because all electrodes worked fine during the recording. Also, the data sets with the error are quite as heavy in terms of bytes as those without the error. Further, why should the RM and LEOG channels remain perfectly well as they do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue might seem like a simple zoom I&#39;ve bypassed, or similar&amp;hellip; But unfortunately the channels are just not there. I&#39;ve confirmed it as I tried to copy the pipeline from the good data sets onto the faulty ones, where I got the error &amp;lsquo;No channels enabled.&amp;rsquo; In case you had access to the BVA analysis software, please find the raw files for one of the faulty data sets here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to invaluable help from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/post/EEG_error_datasets_missing_channels_Its_strange_because_they_were_recorded_well_and_faulty_files_are_quite_as_heavy_as_the_good_ones_Any_ideas&#34;&gt;ResearchGate contributor&lt;/a&gt; and the Brain Products team, I could put the pieces back together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: Problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Nikolay said, the error originated in Recorder (I had used the workspace from the previous experimenter), and the problem was solved by setting the label and position of each channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried editing the .vhdr file in raw (it seemed nice and quick to directly assign the channel names as labels) but i didn&#39;t quite find the way. Therefore, with a tip from the Brain Products team, I went about it within the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I used the transform function &amp;lsquo;Edit channels&amp;rsquo; to rename all labels and set each within their coordinates. I did that for just one subject (it doesn&#39;t take as long as it sounds). Afterwards, I created a &amp;lsquo;History template&amp;rsquo; out of that process, and copied it to all other nodes.
At any rate, never getting out of the comfort workspace again&amp;hellip; :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class = &#39;hanging-indent&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambrosi, S., Kalenine, S., Blaye, A., &amp;amp; Bonthoux, F. (2011). Modality switching cost during property verification by 7 years of age. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Development, 35&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 78-83.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aurlien, H., Gjerde, I., Aarseth, J., Eldøen, G., Karlsen, B., Skeidsvoll, H., &amp;amp; Gilhus, N. (2003).
EEG background activity described by a large computerized database. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Neurophysiology, 115&lt;/em&gt;, 665–673.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, P., Willems, R. M., &amp;amp; Louwerse, M. M. (2017). Modality switch effects emerge early and increase throughout conceptual processing: evidence from ERPs. In G. Gunzelmann, A. Howes, T. Tenbrink, &amp;amp; E. J. Davelaar (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1629-1634). Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collins, J., Pecher, D., Zeelenberg, R., &amp;amp; Coulson, S. (2011). Modality switching in a property verification task: an ERP study of what happens when candles flicker after high heels click. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connell, L., &amp;amp; Lynott, D. (2013). Flexible and fast: Linguistic shortcut affects both shallow and deep conceptual processing. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 20&lt;/em&gt;, 542-550.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di Flumeri, G., Aricò, P., Borghini, G., Sciaraffa, N., Di Florio, A., &amp;amp; Babiloni, F. (2019). The Dry Revolution: Evaluation of Three Different EEG Dry Electrode Types in Terms of Signal Spectral Features, Mental States Classification and Usability. &lt;em&gt;Sensors (Basel, Switzerland), 19&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1365.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gratton, G., Coles, M. G., &amp;amp; Donchin, E. (1983). A new method for offline removal of ocular artefact. &lt;em&gt;Electroencephalography and Clinical Neurophysiology, 55&lt;/em&gt;, 4, 468-484.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hald, L. A., Hocking, I., Vernon, D., Marshall, J.-A., &amp;amp; Garnham, A. (2013). Exploring modality switching effects in negated sentences: further evidence for grounded representations. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 4&lt;/em&gt;, 93.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hald, L. A., Marshall, J.-A., Janssen, D. P., &amp;amp; Garnham, A. (2011). Switching modalities in a sentence verification task: ERP evidence for embodied language processing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hauk, O. (2016). Only time will tell—Why temporal information is essential for our neuroscientific understanding of semantics. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 23&lt;/em&gt;, 4, 1072-1079.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kutas, M., &amp;amp; Federmeier, K. D. (2011). Thirty years and counting: finding meaning in the N400 component of the event-related brain potential (ERP). &lt;em&gt;Annual Review of Psychology, 62&lt;/em&gt;, 621–647.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laszlo, S., Ruiz-Blondet, M., Khalifian, N., Chu, F., &amp;amp; Jin, Z. (2014). A direct comparison of active and passive amplification electrodes in the same amplifier system. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 235&lt;/em&gt;, 298-307.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lebois, L. A. M., Wilson-Mendenhall, C. D., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. W. (2014). Are automatic conceptual cores the gold standard of semantic processing? The context-dependence of spatial meaning in grounded congruency effects. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science, 39&lt;/em&gt;, 8, 1764-801.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leonard, M. K., Baud, M. O., Sjerps, M. J., &amp;amp; Chang, E. F. (2016). Perceptual restoration of masked speech in human cortex. &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications, 7&lt;/em&gt;, 13619.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luck, S. J. &amp;amp; Kappenman, E.S. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Oxford Handbook of Event-Related Potential Components&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Oxford University Press&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mahon, B.Z., &amp;amp; Caramazza, A. (2008). A critical look at the Embodied Cognition Hypothesis and a new proposal for grounding conceptual content. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Physiology - Paris, 102&lt;/em&gt;, 59-70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marques, J. F. (2006). Specialization and semantic organization: Evidence for multiple semantics linked to sensory modalities. *&lt;em&gt;Memory &amp;amp; Cognition, 34&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 60-67.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mordkoff, J. T., &amp;amp; Gianaros, P. J. (2000). Detecting the onset of the lateralized readiness potential: A comparison of available methods and procedures. &lt;em&gt;Psychophysiology, 37&lt;/em&gt;(3), 347–360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pecher, D., Zeelenberg, R., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. W. (2003). Verifying different-modality properties for concepts produces switching costs. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science, 14&lt;/em&gt;, 2, 119-24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ (2004). Sensorimotor simulations underlie conceptual representations: Modality-specific effects of prior activation. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 11&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 164-167.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pexman, P. M., Muraki, E. J., Sidhu, D. M., Siakaluk, P. D., &amp;amp; Yap, M. J. (2019). Quantifying sensorimotor experience: Body-object interaction ratings for more than 9,000 English words. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods, 51&lt;/em&gt;, 453-466.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulvermüller, F., Shtyrov, Y., &amp;amp; Hauk, O. (2009). Understanding in an instant: Neurophysiological evidence for mechanistic language circuits in the brain. &lt;em&gt;Brain and Language, 110&lt;/em&gt;, 2, 81–94.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roohi-Azizi, M., Azimi, L., Heysieattalab, S., &amp;amp; Aamidfar, M. (2017). Changes of the brain&#39;s bioelectrical activity in cognition, consciousness, and some mental disorders. &lt;em&gt;Medical journal of the Islamic Republic of Iran, 31&lt;/em&gt;, 53.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sato, M., Mengarelli, M., Riggio, L., Gallese, V., &amp;amp; Buccino, G. (2008). Task related modulation of the motor system during language processing. &lt;em&gt;Brain and Language, 105&lt;/em&gt;, 83–90.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scerrati, E., Baroni, G., Borghi, A. M., Galatolo, R., Lugli, L., &amp;amp; Nicoletti, R. (2015). The modality-switch effect: visually and aurally presented prime sentences activate our senses. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 6&lt;/em&gt;, 1668.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shtyrov, Y., Hauk, O., &amp;amp; Pulvermüller, F. (2004). Distributed neuronal networks for encoding category-specific semantic information: the mismatch negativity to action words. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Neuroscience, 1&lt;/em&gt;, 4, 1083–1092.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solomon, K. O., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. W. (2004). Perceptual simulation in property verification. &lt;em&gt;Memory &amp;amp; Cognition, 32&lt;/em&gt;, 244-259.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swaab, T.Y., Ledoux, K., Camblin, C.C., &amp;amp; Boudewyn, M.A. (2012) Language related ERP components. (Book Chapter). In Luck, S. J. &amp;amp; Kappenman, E.S. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Oxford Handbook of Event-Related Potential Components&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 397-440). New York: Oxford University Press&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Dantzig, S., Pecher, D., Zeelenberg, R., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. W. (2008). Perceptual processing affects conceptual processing. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science, 32&lt;/em&gt;, 579–590.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Hell, J. G., &amp;amp; Kroll, J. F. (2013). Using electrophysiological measures to track the mapping of words to concepts in the bilingual brain: a focus on translation. In J. Altarriba &amp;amp; L. Isurin (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Memory, Language, and Bilingualism: Theoretical and Applied Approaches&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 126-160). New York: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Vliet, M., Manyakov, N., Storms, G., Fias, W., Wiersema, J., &amp;amp; Van Hulle, M. (2014). Response-Related Potentials during semantic priming: the effect of a speeded button response task on ERPs. &lt;em&gt;PLoS One, 9&lt;/em&gt;, 2, e87650.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vermeulen, N., Niedenthal, P. M., &amp;amp; Luminet, O. (2007). Switching between sensory and affective systems incurs processing costs. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science, 31&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 183-192.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willems, R. M., Frank, S. L., Nijhoff, A. D., Hagoort, P., &amp;amp; Van den Bosch, A. (2016). Prediction during natural language comprehension. &lt;em&gt;Cerebral Cortex, 26&lt;/em&gt;, 6, 2506-2516.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modality switches occur early and extend late in conceptual processing: Evidence from ERPs</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/publication/bernabeu-2017-mphil-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/publication/bernabeu-2017-mphil-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class = &#39;hanging-indent&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, P. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Modality switches occur early and extend late in conceptual processing: Evidence from ERPs&lt;/em&gt;. PsyArXiv. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/5gjvk&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/5gjvk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-podcast&#34;&gt;Related podcast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-wand-magic-sparkles&#34; style=&#39;color:darkgrey;&#39;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style=&#39;color:darkgrey; font-style:italic; font-size:85%;&#39;&gt;Created using Google Gemini and NotebookLM.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&#34;autoplay *; encrypted-media *; fullscreen *; clipboard-write&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;175&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;max-width:660px;overflow:hidden;border-radius:10px;&#34; sandbox=&#34;allow-forms allow-popups allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-storage-access-by-user-activation allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation&#34; src=&#34;https://embed.podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/behind-the-curtains-methods-used-to-investigate/id1837010092?i=1000725594999&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-references&#34;&gt;Related references&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class = &#39;related-references&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class = &#39;hanging-indent&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ali Qurbi, E. (2022). Ambiguous Word Processing among Second Language Learners. &lt;em&gt;The Canadian Modern Language Review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;78&lt;/em&gt;(2), 151&amp;ndash;173. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3138/cmlr-2020-0115&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3138/cmlr-2020-0115&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amenta, S., Crepaldi, D., &amp;amp; Marelli, M. (2020). Consistency measures individuate dissociating semantic modulations in priming paradigms: A new look on semantics in the processing of (complex) words. &lt;em&gt;Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;73&lt;/em&gt;(10), 1546&amp;ndash;1563. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021820927663&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021820927663&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amsel, B. D., Kutas, M., &amp;amp; Coulson, S. (2017). Projectors, associators, visual imagery, and the time course of visual processing in grapheme-color synesthesia. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(4), 206&amp;ndash;223. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/17588928.2017.1353492&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/17588928.2017.1353492&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argiris, G., Rumiati, R. I., &amp;amp; Crepaldi, D. (2021). No fruits without color: Cross-modal priming and EEG reveal different roles for different features across semantic categories. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(4), e0234219. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0234219&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0234219&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avramova, Y. R., De Pelsmacker, P., &amp;amp; Dens, N. (2017). Brand placement in text: The short- and long-term effects of placement modality and need for cognition. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Advertising&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;36&lt;/em&gt;(5), 682&amp;ndash;704. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/02650487.2017.1335041&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/02650487.2017.1335041&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bagli, M. (2023). How to Point with Language: English Source-Based Language to Describe Taste Qualities. &lt;em&gt;Lublin Studies in Modern Languages and Literature&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;42&lt;/em&gt;(2), 31&amp;ndash;46. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.17951/lsmll.2023.47.2.31-46&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.17951/lsmll.2023.47.2.31-46&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks, B., Wingfield, C., &amp;amp; Connell, L. (2021). Linguistic Distributional Knowledge and Sensorimotor Grounding both Contribute to Semantic Category Production. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;45&lt;/em&gt;(10), e13055. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.13055&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.13055&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barros García, B. (2017). In Other Words: Reformulation Strategies in Dostoevskii&#39;s Literary Works. &lt;em&gt;Russian Literature&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;91&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;25. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ruslit.2017.09.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ruslit.2017.09.001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barsalou, L. W. (2017a). Cognitively Plausible Theories of Concept Composition. In J. A. Hampton &amp;amp; Y. Winter (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Compositionality and Concepts in Linguistics and Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 3, pp. 9&amp;ndash;30). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-45977-6_2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-45977-6_2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barsalou, L. W. (2017b). What does semantic tiling of the cortex tell us about semantics? &lt;em&gt;Neuropsychologia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;105&lt;/em&gt;, 18&amp;ndash;38. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2017.04.011&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2017.04.011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barsalou, L. W. (2020). Challenges and Opportunities for Grounding Cognition. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(1), 31. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5334/joc.116&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5334/joc.116&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bartl, S., &amp;amp; Lahey, E. (2023). &amp;lsquo;As the title implies&amp;rsquo;: How readers talk about titles in Amazon book reviews. &lt;em&gt;Language and Literature: International Journal of Stylistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;32&lt;/em&gt;(2), 209&amp;ndash;230. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/09639470221147788&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/09639470221147788&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baumann, A., Hofmann, K., Marakasova, A., Neidhardt, J., &amp;amp; Wissik, T. (2023). Semantic micro-dynamics as a reflex of occurrence frequency: A semantic networks approach. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;34&lt;/em&gt;(3&amp;ndash;4), 533&amp;ndash;568. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/cog-2022-0008&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1515/cog-2022-0008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bechtold, L., Bellebaum, C., Egan, S., Tettamanti, M., &amp;amp; Ghio, M. (2019). The role of experience for abstract concepts: Expertise modulates the electrophysiological correlates of mathematical word processing. &lt;em&gt;Brain and Language&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;188&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;10. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandl.2018.10.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandl.2018.10.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bechtold, L., Bellebaum, C., &amp;amp; Ghio, M. (2023). When a Sunny Day Gives You Butterflies: An Electrophysiological Investigation of Concreteness and Context Effects in Semantic Word Processing. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;35&lt;/em&gt;(2), 241&amp;ndash;258. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn_a_01942&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn_a_01942&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bechtold, L., Bellebaum, C., Hoffman, P., &amp;amp; Ghio, M. (2021). Corroborating behavioral evidence for the interplay of representational richness and semantic control in semantic word processing. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(1), 6184. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-85711-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-85711-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bidet-Ildei, C., Gimenes, M., Toussaint, L., Almecija, Y., &amp;amp; Badets, A. (2017). Sentence plausibility influences the link between action words and the perception of biological human movements. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;81&lt;/em&gt;(4), 806&amp;ndash;813. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-016-0776-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-016-0776-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bidet-Ildei, C., Gimenes, M., Toussaint, L., Beauprez, S.-A., &amp;amp; Badets, A. (2017). Painful semantic context modulates the relationship between action words and biological movement perception. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognitive Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(7), 821&amp;ndash;831. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/20445911.2017.1322093&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/20445911.2017.1322093&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolognesi, M., &amp;amp; Strik Lievers, F. (2020). How language and image construct synaesthetic metaphors in print advertising. &lt;em&gt;Visual Communication&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(4), 431&amp;ndash;457. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1470357218782001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1470357218782001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borghesani, V., &amp;amp; Piazza, M. (2017). The neuro-cognitive representations of symbols: The case of concrete words. &lt;em&gt;Neuropsychologia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;105&lt;/em&gt;, 4&amp;ndash;17. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2017.06.026&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2017.06.026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borghi, A. M., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. (2021). Perspective in the conceptualization of categories. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;85&lt;/em&gt;(2), 697&amp;ndash;719. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-019-01269-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-019-01269-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borghi, A. M., Binkofski, F., Castelfranchi, C., Cimatti, F., Scorolli, C., &amp;amp; Tummolini, L. (2017). The challenge of abstract concepts. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;143&lt;/em&gt;(3), 263&amp;ndash;292. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/bul0000089&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/bul0000089&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borghi, A. M., Mazzuca, C., Gervasi, A. M., Mannella, F., &amp;amp; Tummolini, L. (2023). Grounded cognition can be multimodal all the way down. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;5. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2023.2210238&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2023.2210238&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottini, R., Ferraro, S., Nigri, A., Cuccarini, V., Bruzzone, M. G., &amp;amp; Collignon, O. (2020). Brain Regions Involved in Conceptual Retrieval in Sighted and Blind People. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;32&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1009&amp;ndash;1025. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn_a_01538&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn_a_01538&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruffaerts, R., De Deyne, S., Meersmans, K., Liuzzi, A. G., Storms, G., &amp;amp; Vandenberghe, R. (2019). Redefining the resolution of semantic knowledge in the brain: Advances made by the introduction of models of semantics in neuroimaging. &lt;em&gt;Neuroscience &amp;amp; Biobehavioral Reviews&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;103&lt;/em&gt;, 3&amp;ndash;13. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2019.05.015&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2019.05.015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caballero, R., &amp;amp; Paradis, C. (2020). Soundscapes in English and Spanish: A corpus investigation of verb constructions. &lt;em&gt;Language and Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(4), 705&amp;ndash;728. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2020.19&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2020.19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caballero, R., &amp;amp; Paradis, C. (2023). Sharing Perceptual Experiences through Language. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;(7), 129. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/jintelligence11070129&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/jintelligence11070129&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cantarero, K., Parzuchowski, M., &amp;amp; Dukala, K. (2017). White Lies in Hand: Are Other-Oriented Lies Modified by Hand Gestures? Possibly Not. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 814. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00814&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00814&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carney, J. (2020). Thinking avant la lettre: A Review of 4E Cognition. &lt;em&gt;Evolutionary Studies in Imaginative Culture&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(1), 77&amp;ndash;90. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.26613/esic.4.1.172&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.26613/esic.4.1.172&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caterina Villani &amp;amp; Luisa Lugli. (2020). L&#39;effetto Simon e il suo decorso temporale con stimoli linguistici non spaziali. &lt;em&gt;Giornale italiano di psicologia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;, 305&amp;ndash;314. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1421/96612&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1421/96612&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chan, S. (2022). Dynamics of nominal classification systems in language processing. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;37&lt;/em&gt;(6), 671&amp;ndash;685. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2021.2011331&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2021.2011331&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charmhun Jo, Sun-A Kim, &amp;amp; Chu-Ren Huang. (2022). Linguistic synesthesia in Korean: A compound word-based study of cross-modal directionality. &lt;em&gt;Linguistic Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;39&lt;/em&gt;(2), 275&amp;ndash;296. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.17250/KHISLI.39.2.202206.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.17250/KHISLI.39.2.202206.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chedid, G., Brambati, S. M., Bedetti, C., Rey, A. E., Wilson, M. A., &amp;amp; Vallet, G. T. (2019). Visual and auditory perceptual strength norms for 3,596 French nouns and their relationship with other psycholinguistic variables. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;51&lt;/em&gt;(5), 2094&amp;ndash;2105. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01254-w&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01254-w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen, I.-H., Zhao, Q., Long, Y., Lu, Q., &amp;amp; Huang, C.-R. (2019). Mandarin Chinese modality exclusivity norms. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(2), e0211336. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0211336&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0211336&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choi, U., Sung, Y., &amp;amp; Ogawa, S. (2020). Measurement of ultra‐fast signal progression related to face processing by 7T fMRI. &lt;em&gt;Human Brain Mapping&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;41&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1754&amp;ndash;1764. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.24907&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.24907&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chwilla, D. J. (2022). Context effects in language comprehension: The role of emotional state and attention on semantic and syntactic processing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, 1014547. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2022.1014547&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2022.1014547&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cirillo, G., Strijkers, K., Runnqvist, E., &amp;amp; Baus, C. (2023). Effects of Shared Attention on joint language production across processing stages. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;12. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2023.2260021&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2023.2260021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cochrane, B. A., &amp;amp; Milliken, B. (2019). Imagined event files: An interplay between imagined and perceived objects. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(2), 538&amp;ndash;544. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-019-01572-2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-019-01572-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connell, L. (2019). What have labels ever done for us? The linguistic shortcut in conceptual processing. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;34&lt;/em&gt;(10), 1308&amp;ndash;1318. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2018.1471512&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2018.1471512&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connell, L., Lynott, D., &amp;amp; Banks, B. (2018). Interoception: The forgotten modality in perceptual grounding of abstract and concrete concepts. &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;373&lt;/em&gt;(1752), 20170143. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2017.0143&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2017.0143&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corciulo, S., Bioglio, L., Basile, V., Patti, V., &amp;amp; Damiano, R. (2023). The DEEP Sensorium: A multidimensional approach to sensory domain labelling. &lt;em&gt;Companion Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference 2023&lt;/em&gt;, 661&amp;ndash;668. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1145/3543873.3587631&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1145/3543873.3587631&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courson, M., Macoir, J., &amp;amp; Tremblay, P. (2018). A facilitating role for the primary motor cortex in action sentence processing. &lt;em&gt;Behavioural Brain Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;336&lt;/em&gt;, 244&amp;ndash;249. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2017.09.019&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2017.09.019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis, C. P., Joergensen, G. H., Boddy, P., Dowling, C., &amp;amp; Yee, E. (2020). Making It Harder to &amp;ldquo;See&amp;rdquo; Meaning: The More You See Something, the More Its Conceptual Representation Is Susceptible to Visual Interference. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;31&lt;/em&gt;(5), 505&amp;ndash;517. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797620910748&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797620910748&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis, C. P., &amp;amp; Yee, E. (2021). Building semantic memory from embodied and distributional language experience. &lt;em&gt;WIREs Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(5), e1555. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/wcs.1555&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/wcs.1555&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis, J. D., Coulson, S., Arnold, A. J., &amp;amp; Winkielman, P. (2021). Dynamic Grounding of Concepts: Implications for Emotion and Social Cognition. In M. D. Robinson &amp;amp; L. E. Thomas (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Embodied Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 23&amp;ndash;42). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-78471-3_2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-78471-3_2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Deyne, S., Brysbaert, M., &amp;amp; Elgort, I. (2023). Chapter 7. Cross-language influences in L2 semantic and conceptual representation and processing. In I. Elgort, A. Siyanova-Chanturia, &amp;amp; M. Brysbaert (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Bilingual Processing and Acquisition&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 16, pp. 152&amp;ndash;186). John Benjamins Publishing Company. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/bpa.16.07ded&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/bpa.16.07ded&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dellantonio, S., &amp;amp; Pastore, L. (2017). The &amp;lsquo;Proprioceptive&amp;rsquo; Component of Abstract Concepts. In S. Dellantonio &amp;amp; L. Pastore, &lt;em&gt;Internal Perception&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 40, pp. 297&amp;ndash;357). Springer Berlin Heidelberg. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-662-55763-1_6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-662-55763-1_6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Díez-Álamo, A. M., Díez, E., Alonso, M. Á., Vargas, C. A., &amp;amp; Fernandez, A. (2018). Normative ratings for perceptual and motor attributes of 750 object concepts in Spanish. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;50&lt;/em&gt;(4), 1632&amp;ndash;1644. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-017-0970-y&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-017-0970-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove, G. (2018). Language as a disruptive technology: Abstract concepts, embodiment and the flexible mind. &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;373&lt;/em&gt;(1752), 20170135. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2017.0135&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2017.0135&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove, G. (2021). The Challenges of Abstract Concepts. In M. D. Robinson &amp;amp; L. E. Thomas (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Embodied Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 171&amp;ndash;195). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-78471-3_8&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-78471-3_8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove, G., Barca, L., Tummolini, L., &amp;amp; Borghi, A. M. (2022). Words have a weight: Language as a source of inner grounding and flexibility in abstract concepts. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;86&lt;/em&gt;(8), 2451&amp;ndash;2467. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-020-01438-6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-020-01438-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dupont, W., Papaxanthis, C., Lebon, F., &amp;amp; Madden-Lombardi, C. (2022). Does the Motor Cortex Want the Full Story? The Influence of Sentence Context on Corticospinal Excitability in Action Language Processing. &lt;em&gt;Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;506&lt;/em&gt;, 58&amp;ndash;67. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2022.10.022&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2022.10.022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dutriaux, L., Dahiez, X., &amp;amp; Gyselinck, V. (2019). How to change your memory of an object with a posture and a verb. &lt;em&gt;Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;72&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1112&amp;ndash;1118. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021818785096&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021818785096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dymarska, A., Connell, L., &amp;amp; Banks, B. (2022). Linguistic Bootstrapping Allows More Real-world Object Concepts to Be Held in Mind. &lt;em&gt;Collabra: Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1), 40171. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1525/collabra.40171&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1525/collabra.40171&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dymarska, A., Connell, L., &amp;amp; Banks, B. (2023). More is not necessarily better: How different aspects of sensorimotor experience affect recognition memory for words. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(10), 1572&amp;ndash;1587. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0001265&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0001265&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edmiston, P., &amp;amp; Lupyan, G. (2017). Visual interference disrupts visual knowledge. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Memory and Language&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;92&lt;/em&gt;, 281&amp;ndash;292. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jml.2016.07.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jml.2016.07.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elisa Scerrati, Cristina Iani, Luisa Lugli, &amp;amp; Sandro Rubichi. (2019). C&#39;è un effetto di potenziamento dell&#39;azione con oggetti bimanuali? &lt;em&gt;Giornale italiano di psicologia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 987&amp;ndash;996. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1421/95573&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1421/95573&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elpidorou, A., &amp;amp; Dove, G. (2018). &lt;em&gt;Consciousness and Physicalism: A Defense of a Research Program&lt;/em&gt; (1st ed.). Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315682075&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315682075&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Espino, O., &amp;amp; Byrne, R. M. J. (2018). Thinking About the Opposite of What Is Said: Counterfactual Conditionals and Symbolic or Alternate Simulations of Negation. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;42&lt;/em&gt;(8), 2459&amp;ndash;2501. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12677&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12677&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fabrizio Calzavarini. (2023). Comprensione e cervello. &lt;em&gt;Sistemi intelligenti&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt;, 251&amp;ndash;276. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1422/107149&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1422/107149&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fischer, J., &amp;amp; Mahon, B. Z. (2021). What tool representation, intuitive physics, and action have in common: The brain&#39;s first-person physics engine. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuropsychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;38&lt;/em&gt;(7&amp;ndash;8), 455&amp;ndash;467. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/02643294.2022.2106126&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/02643294.2022.2106126&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galetzka, C. (2017). The Story So Far: How Embodied Cognition Advances Our Understanding of Meaning-Making. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 1315. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.01315&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.01315&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gálvez-García, G., Aldunate, N., Bascour-Sandoval, C., Martínez-Molina, A., Peña, J., &amp;amp; Barramuño, M. (2020). Muscle activation in semantic processing: An electromyography approach. &lt;em&gt;Biological Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;152&lt;/em&gt;, 107881. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsycho.2020.107881&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsycho.2020.107881&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gao, C., Baucom, L. B., Kim, J., Wang, J., Wedell, D. H., &amp;amp; Shinkareva, S. V. (2019). Distinguishing abstract from concrete concepts in supramodal brain regions. &lt;em&gt;Neuropsychologia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;131&lt;/em&gt;, 102&amp;ndash;110. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2019.05.032&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2019.05.032&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatti, D., Marelli, M., Vecchi, T., &amp;amp; Rinaldi, L. (2022). Spatial Representations Without Spatial Computations. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(11), 1947&amp;ndash;1958. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/09567976221094863&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/09567976221094863&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gijssels, T., &amp;amp; Casasanto, D. (2020). Hand-use norms for Dutch and English manual action verbs: Implicit measures from a pantomime task. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;52&lt;/em&gt;(4), 1744&amp;ndash;1767. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-020-01347-x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-020-01347-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grand, G., Blank, I. A., Pereira, F., &amp;amp; Fedorenko, E. (2022). Semantic projection recovers rich human knowledge of multiple object features from word embeddings. &lt;em&gt;Nature Human Behaviour&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(7), 975&amp;ndash;987. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-022-01316-8&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-022-01316-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant, L. D., &amp;amp; Weissman, D. H. (2023). The binary structure of event files generalizes to abstract features: A nonhierarchical explanation of task set boundaries for the congruency sequence effect. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1033&amp;ndash;1050. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0001148&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0001148&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greco, A. (2021). Spatial and Motor Aspects in the &amp;ldquo;Action-Sentence Compatibility Effect.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 647899. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.647899&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.647899&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guerra, E., &amp;amp; Knoeferle, P. (2018). Semantic Interference and Facilitation: Understanding the Integration of Spatial Distance and Conceptual Similarity During Sentence Reading. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 718. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00718&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00718&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Günther, F., Petilli, M. A., Vergallito, A., &amp;amp; Marelli, M. (2022). Images of the unseen: Extrapolating visual representations for abstract and concrete words in a data-driven computational model. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;86&lt;/em&gt;(8), 2512&amp;ndash;2532. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-020-01429-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-020-01429-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Günther, F., Rinaldi, L., &amp;amp; Marelli, M. (2019). Vector-Space Models of Semantic Representation From a Cognitive Perspective: A Discussion of Common Misconceptions. &lt;em&gt;Perspectives on Psychological Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1006&amp;ndash;1033. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691619861372&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691619861372&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hafri, A., Trueswell, J. C., &amp;amp; Strickland, B. (2018). Encoding of event roles from visual scenes is rapid, spontaneous, and interacts with higher-level visual processing. &lt;em&gt;Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;175&lt;/em&gt;, 36&amp;ndash;52. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.02.011&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.02.011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardy, B. W. (2021). Embodied Cognition in Communication Science. &lt;em&gt;Communication Theory&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;31&lt;/em&gt;(4), 633&amp;ndash;653. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/ct/qtaa003&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/ct/qtaa003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harpaintner, M., Sim, E.-J., Trumpp, N. M., Ulrich, M., &amp;amp; Kiefer, M. (2020). The grounding of abstract concepts in the motor and visual system: An fMRI study. &lt;em&gt;Cortex&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;124&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;22. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2019.10.014&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2019.10.014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harpaintner, M., Trumpp, N. M., &amp;amp; Kiefer, M. (2018). The Semantic Content of Abstract Concepts: A Property Listing Study of 296 Abstract Words. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 1748. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01748&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01748&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harpaintner, M., Trumpp, N. M., &amp;amp; Kiefer, M. (2022). Time course of brain activity during the processing of motor- and vision-related abstract concepts: Flexibility and task dependency. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;86&lt;/em&gt;(8), 2560&amp;ndash;2582. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-020-01374-5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-020-01374-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hartman, J., &amp;amp; Paradis, C. (2023). The language of sound: Events and meaning multitasking of words. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;34&lt;/em&gt;(3&amp;ndash;4), 445&amp;ndash;477. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/cog-2022-0006&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1515/cog-2022-0006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hauk, O., Giraud, A.-L., &amp;amp; Clarke, A. (2017). Brain oscillations in language comprehension. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;32&lt;/em&gt;(5), 533&amp;ndash;535. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2017.1297842&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2017.1297842&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hauk, O., Jackson, R. L., &amp;amp; Rahimi, S. (2023). Transforming the neuroscience of language: Estimating pattern-to-pattern transformations of brain activity. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;16. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2023.2226268&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2023.2226268&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hauk, O., Magnabosco, F., &amp;amp; Law, R. (2023). Can we separate semantic representations from computations? A commentary on Calzavarini (2023). &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;4. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2023.2226269&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2023.2226269&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heim, E. M. (2017a). &lt;em&gt;Adoption in Galatians and Romans: Contemporary Metaphor Theories and the Pauline Huiothesia Metaphors&lt;/em&gt;. BRILL. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1163/9789004339873&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1163/9789004339873&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heim, E. M. (2017b). &lt;em&gt;Adoption in Galatians and Romans: Contemporary Metaphor Theories and the Pauline Huiothesia Metaphors&lt;/em&gt;. BRILL. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1163/9789004339873&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1163/9789004339873&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoeben Mannaert, L. N., Dijkstra, K., &amp;amp; Zwaan, R. A. (2020). Object combination in mental simulations. &lt;em&gt;Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;73&lt;/em&gt;(11), 1796&amp;ndash;1806. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021820933214&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021820933214&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoffman, P., McClelland, J. L., &amp;amp; Lambon Ralph, M. A. (2018). Concepts, control, and context: A connectionist account of normal and disordered semantic cognition. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;125&lt;/em&gt;(3), 293&amp;ndash;328. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000094&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000094&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hohol, M. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Foundations of Geometric Cognition&lt;/em&gt; (1st ed.). Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429056291&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429056291&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holman, A., &amp;amp; Gîrbă, A. (2019). The match in orientation between verbal context and object accelerates change detection. &lt;em&gt;Psihologija&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;52&lt;/em&gt;(1), 93&amp;ndash;105. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2298/PSI180412033H&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2298/PSI180412033H&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hörberg, T., Larsson, M., &amp;amp; Olofsson, J. K. (2022). The Semantic Organization of the English Odor Vocabulary. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;46&lt;/em&gt;(11), e13205. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.13205&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.13205&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huang, C.-R., &amp;amp; Xiong, J. (2019). Linguistic synaesthesia in Chinese. In C.-R. Huang, Z. Jing-Schmidt, &amp;amp; B. Meisterernst (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Routledge Handbook of Chinese Applied Linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (1st ed., pp. 294&amp;ndash;312). Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315625157-20&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315625157-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iatropoulos, G., Herman, P., Lansner, A., Karlgren, J., Larsson, M., &amp;amp; Olofsson, J. K. (2018). The language of smell: Connecting linguistic and psychophysical properties of odor descriptors. &lt;em&gt;Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;178&lt;/em&gt;, 37&amp;ndash;49. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.05.007&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.05.007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iriguchi, M., Fujimura, R., Koda, H., &amp;amp; Masataka, N. (2019). Traffic symbol recognition modulates bodily actions. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;(3), e0214281. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0214281&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0214281&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jo, C. (2022). Linguistic Synesthesia in Korean: Universality and Variation. &lt;em&gt;SAGE Open&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(3), 215824402211178. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/21582440221117804&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/21582440221117804&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johns, B. T. (2022). Accounting for item-level variance in recognition memory: Comparing word frequency and contextual diversity. &lt;em&gt;Memory &amp;amp; Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;50&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1013&amp;ndash;1032. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-021-01249-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-021-01249-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones, L. L., Wurm, L. H., Calcaterra, R. D., &amp;amp; Ofen, N. (2017). Integrative Priming of Compositional and Locative Relations. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00359&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00359&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julich-Warpakowski, N., &amp;amp; Pérez Sobrino, P. (2023). Introduction: Current challenges in metaphor research. &lt;em&gt;Metaphor and the Social World&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 1&amp;ndash;15. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/msw.00026.jul&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/msw.00026.jul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kabbach, A., &amp;amp; Herbelot, A. (2021). Avoiding Conflict: When Speaker Coordination Does Not Require Conceptual Agreement. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;, 523920. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/frai.2020.523920&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/frai.2020.523920&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaiser, E. (2021). Consequences of Sensory Modality for Perspective-Taking: Comparing Visual, Olfactory and Gustatory Perception. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 701486. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.701486&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.701486&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaup, B., Ulrich, R., Bausenhart, K. M., Bryce, D., Butz, M. V., Dignath, D., Dudschig, C., Franz, V. H., Friedrich, C., Gawrilow, C., Heller, J., Huff, M., Hütter, M., Janczyk, M., Leuthold, H., Mallot, H., Nürk, H.-C., Ramscar, M., Said, N., &amp;hellip; Wong, H. Y. (2023). Modal and amodal cognition: An overarching principle in various domains of psychology. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Research&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-023-01878-w&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-023-01878-w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keogh, R., &amp;amp; Pearson, J. (2017). The perceptual and phenomenal capacity of mental imagery. &lt;em&gt;Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;162&lt;/em&gt;, 124&amp;ndash;132. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2017.02.004&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2017.02.004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kernot, D., Bossomaier, T., &amp;amp; Bradbury, R. (2017). Novel Text Analysis for Investigating Personality: Identifying the Dark Lady in Shakespeare&#39;s Sonnets. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Quantitative Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;24&lt;/em&gt;(4), 255&amp;ndash;272. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/09296174.2017.1304049&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/09296174.2017.1304049&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kernot, D., Bossomaier, T., &amp;amp; Bradbury, R. (2018). Using Shakespeare&#39;s Sotto Voce to Determine True Identity From Text. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 289. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00289&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kernot, D., Bossomaier, T., &amp;amp; Bradbury, R. (2019). The Stylometric Impacts of Ageing and Life Events on Identity. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Quantitative Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(1), 1&amp;ndash;21. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/09296174.2017.1405719&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/09296174.2017.1405719&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keus, K., &amp;amp; Harde, R. (2022). &amp;ldquo;She Wished Someone Would Help Them&amp;rdquo;: PTSD and Empathy in the Six of Crows Duology. &lt;em&gt;Children&#39;s Literature in Education&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;(1), 130&amp;ndash;146. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10583-021-09441-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10583-021-09441-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Khatin-Zadeh, O., Hu, J., Banaruee, H., &amp;amp; Marmolejo-Ramos, F. (2023). How emotions are metaphorically embodied: Measuring hand and head action strengths of typical emotional states. &lt;em&gt;Cognition and Emotion&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;37&lt;/em&gt;(3), 486&amp;ndash;498. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/02699931.2023.2181314&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/02699931.2023.2181314&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim, M.-K., Müller, H. M., &amp;amp; Weiss, S. (2021). What you &amp;ldquo;mean&amp;rdquo; is not what I &amp;ldquo;mean&amp;rdquo;: Categorization of verbs by Germans and Koreans using the semantic differential. &lt;em&gt;Lingua&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;252&lt;/em&gt;, 103012. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lingua.2020.103012&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lingua.2020.103012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klomberg, B., Schilhab, T., &amp;amp; Burke, M. (2022). &lt;em&gt;Picturing Fiction through Embodied Cognition: Drawn Representations and Viewpoint in Literary Texts&lt;/em&gt; (1st ed.). Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781003225300&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781003225300&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knoeferle, P. (2019). Predicting (variability of) context effects in language comprehension. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cultural Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(2), 141&amp;ndash;158. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s41809-019-00025-5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s41809-019-00025-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koblet, O., &amp;amp; Purves, R. S. (2020). From online texts to Landscape Character Assessment: Collecting and analysing first-person landscape perception computationally. &lt;em&gt;Landscape and Urban Planning&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;197&lt;/em&gt;, 103757. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.landurbplan.2020.103757&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.landurbplan.2020.103757&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kompa, N. A. (2021). Language and embodiment&amp;mdash;Or the cognitive benefits of abstract representations. &lt;em&gt;Mind &amp;amp; Language&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;36&lt;/em&gt;(1), 27&amp;ndash;47. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/mila.12266&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/mila.12266&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kompa, N. A., &amp;amp; Mueller, J. L. (2022). Inner speech as a cognitive tool&amp;mdash;Or what is the point of talking to oneself? &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;24. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/09515089.2022.2112164&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/09515089.2022.2112164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Körner, A., Castillo, M., Drijvers, L., Fischer, M. H., Günther, F., Marelli, M., Platonova, O., Rinaldi, L., Shaki, S., Trujillo, J. P., Tsaregorodtseva, O., &amp;amp; Glenberg, A. M. (2023). Embodied Processing at Six Linguistic Granularity Levels: A Consensus Paper. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 60. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5334/joc.231&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5334/joc.231&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krishna, P. P., Arulmozi, S., &amp;amp; Mishra, R. K. (2022). &amp;ldquo;Do You See and Hear More? A Study on Telugu Perception Verbs.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psycholinguistic Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;51&lt;/em&gt;(3), 473&amp;ndash;484. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10936-021-09827-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10936-021-09827-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kuhnke, P., Beaupain, M. C., Arola, J., Kiefer, M., &amp;amp; Hartwigsen, G. (2023). Meta-analytic evidence for a novel hierarchical model of conceptual processing. &lt;em&gt;Neuroscience &amp;amp; Biobehavioral Reviews&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;144&lt;/em&gt;, 104994. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2022.104994&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2022.104994&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kuhnke, P., Kiefer, M., &amp;amp; Hartwigsen, G. (2021). Task-Dependent Functional and Effective Connectivity during Conceptual Processing. &lt;em&gt;Cerebral Cortex&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;31&lt;/em&gt;(7), 3475&amp;ndash;3493. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhab026&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhab026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kumcu, A. (2021). Linguistic Synesthesia in Turkish: A Corpus-based Study of Crossmodal Directionality. &lt;em&gt;Metaphor and Symbol&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;36&lt;/em&gt;(4), 241&amp;ndash;255. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10926488.2021.1921557&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10926488.2021.1921557&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lai, V. T., Hubbard, R., Ku, L.-C., &amp;amp; Pfeifer, V. (2023). Electrophysiology of Non-Literal Language. In M. Grimaldi, E. Brattico, &amp;amp; Y. Shtyrov (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Language Electrified&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 202, pp. 613&amp;ndash;646). Springer US. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-0716-3263-5_19&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-0716-3263-5_19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landrigan, J.-F., &amp;amp; Mirman, D. (2018). The cost of switching between taxonomic and thematic semantics. &lt;em&gt;Memory &amp;amp; Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;46&lt;/em&gt;(2), 191&amp;ndash;203. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-017-0757-5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-017-0757-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large, A.-C., Bach, C., &amp;amp; Calvet, G. (2018). CONTACT: A Human Centered Approach of Multimodal Flight Deck Design and Evaluation. In D. Harris (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Engineering Psychology and Cognitive Ergonomics&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 10906, pp. 593&amp;ndash;604). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-91122-9_48&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-91122-9_48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee, J., &amp;amp; Shin, J.-A. (2023). The cross-linguistic comparison of perceptual strength norms for Korean, English and L2 English. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;14&lt;/em&gt;, 1188909. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1188909&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1188909&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li, M., Lu, Q., Long, Y., &amp;amp; Gui, L. (2017). Inferring Affective Meanings of Words from Word Embedding. &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(4), 443&amp;ndash;456. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/TAFFC.2017.2723012&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/TAFFC.2017.2723012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lin, K., &amp;amp; Chan, S. (2019). When senses meet functions: An amodal stage in conceptual processing. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognitive Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;31&lt;/em&gt;(1), 64&amp;ndash;75. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/20445911.2018.1560299&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/20445911.2018.1560299&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Littlemore, J. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Metaphors in the Mind: Sources of Variation in Embodied Metaphor&lt;/em&gt; (1st ed.). Cambridge University Press. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781108241441&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781108241441&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu, S., Zhou, M., &amp;amp; Li, Y. (2019). Internet use experience influence individuals&amp;rsquo; lexical decision performance by changing their body representation. &lt;em&gt;Computers in Human Behavior&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;91&lt;/em&gt;, 157&amp;ndash;166. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2018.09.021&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2018.09.021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu, W., Bansal, D., Daruna, A., &amp;amp; Chernova, S. (2023). Learning instance-level N-ary semantic knowledge at scale for robots operating in everyday environments. &lt;em&gt;Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;47&lt;/em&gt;(5), 529&amp;ndash;547. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10514-023-10099-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10514-023-10099-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu, W., Bansal, D., Daruna, A., &amp;amp; Chernova, S. (2021, July 12). Learning Instance-Level N-Ary Semantic Knowledge At Scale For Robots Operating in Everyday Environments. &lt;em&gt;Robotics: Science and Systems XVII&lt;/em&gt;. Robotics: Science and Systems 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.15607/RSS.2021.XVII.035&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.15607/RSS.2021.XVII.035&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long, Y., Xiang, R., Lu, Q., Huang, C.-R., &amp;amp; Li, M. (2021). Improving Attention Model Based on Cognition Grounded Data for Sentiment Analysis. &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(4), 900&amp;ndash;912. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/TAFFC.2019.2903056&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/TAFFC.2019.2903056&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Louwerse, M. M. (2018). Knowing the Meaning of a Word by the Linguistic and Perceptual Company It Keeps. &lt;em&gt;Topics in Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(3), 573&amp;ndash;589. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12349&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12349&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lupyan, G., &amp;amp; Winter, B. (2018). Language is more abstract than you think, or, why aren&#39;t languages more iconic? &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;373&lt;/em&gt;(1752), 20170137. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2017.0137&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2017.0137&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lynott, D., Connell, L., Brysbaert, M., Brand, J., &amp;amp; Carney, J. (2020). The Lancaster Sensorimotor Norms: Multidimensional measures of perceptual and action strength for 40,000 English words. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;52&lt;/em&gt;(3), 1271&amp;ndash;1291. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01316-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01316-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lynott, D., Walsh, M., McEnery, T., Connell, L., Cross, L., &amp;amp; O&#39;Brien, K. (2019). Are You What You Read? Predicting Implicit Attitudes to Immigration Based on Linguistic Distributional Cues From Newspaper Readership; A Pre-registered Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 842. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.00842&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.00842&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malhi, S. K., &amp;amp; Buchanan, L. (2018). A test of the symbol interdependency hypothesis with both concrete and abstract stimuli. &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(3), e0192719. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0192719&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0192719&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mangels, J. A., Rodriguez, S., Ochakovskaya, Y., &amp;amp; Guerra-Carrillo, B. (2017). Achievement Goal Task Framing and Fit With Personal Goals Modulate the Neurocognitive Response to Corrective Feedback. &lt;em&gt;AERA Open&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(3), 233285841772087. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/2332858417720875&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/2332858417720875&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marchetti, R., Vaugoyeau, M., Colé, P., &amp;amp; Assaiante, C. (2022). A sensorimotor representation impairment in dyslexic adults: A specific profile of comorbidity. &lt;em&gt;Neuropsychologia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;165&lt;/em&gt;, 108134. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2021.108134&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2021.108134&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marmeleira, J., &amp;amp; Duarte Santos, G. (2019). Do Not Neglect the Body and Action: The Emergence of Embodiment Approaches to Understanding Human Development. &lt;em&gt;Perceptual and Motor Skills&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;126&lt;/em&gt;(3), 410&amp;ndash;445. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0031512519834389&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0031512519834389&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marson, F., Paoletti, P., Naor-Ziv, R., Carducci, F., &amp;amp; Ben-Soussan, T. D. (2023). Embodied empathy and abstract concepts&amp;rsquo; concreteness: Evidence from contemplative practices. In &lt;em&gt;Progress in Brain Research&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 277, pp. 181&amp;ndash;209). Elsevier. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.pbr.2022.12.005&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.pbr.2022.12.005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Márton, Z. C., Türker, S., Rink, C., Brucker, M., Kriegel, S., Bodenmüller, T., &amp;amp; Riedel, S. (2018). Improving object orientation estimates by considering multiple viewpoints: Orientation histograms of symmetries and measurement models for view selection. &lt;em&gt;Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;42&lt;/em&gt;(2), 423&amp;ndash;442. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10514-017-9633-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10514-017-9633-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McRae, K., Nedjadrasul, D., Pau, R., Lo, B. P., &amp;amp; King, L. (2018). Abstract Concepts and Pictures of Real‐World Situations Activate One Another. &lt;em&gt;Topics in Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(3), 518&amp;ndash;532. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12328&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12328&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meng, X., Sun, C., Du, B., Liu, L., Zhang, Y., Dong, Q., Georgiou, G. K., &amp;amp; Nan, Y. (2022). The development of brain rhythms at rest and its impact on vocabulary acquisition. &lt;em&gt;Developmental Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;(2), e13157. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/desc.13157&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/desc.13157&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miceli, A., Wauthia, E., Kandana Arachchige, K., Lefebvre, L., Ris, L., &amp;amp; Simoes Loureiro, I. (2023). Perceptual strength influences lexical decision in Alzheimer&#39;s disease. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Neurolinguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;68&lt;/em&gt;, 101144. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroling.2023.101144&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroling.2023.101144&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miceli, A., Wauthia, E., Lefebvre, L., Ris, L., &amp;amp; Simoes Loureiro, I. (2021). Perceptual and Interoceptive Strength Norms for 270 French Words. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;, 667271. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.667271&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.667271&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miceli, A., Wauthia, E., Lefebvre, L., Vallet, G. T., Ris, L., &amp;amp; Loureiro, I. S. (2022). Differences related to aging in sensorimotor knowledge: Investigation of perceptual strength and body object interaction. &lt;em&gt;Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;102&lt;/em&gt;, 104715. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.archger.2022.104715&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.archger.2022.104715&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miklashevsky, A. (2018). Perceptual Experience Norms for 506 Russian Nouns: Modality Rating, Spatial Localization, Manipulability, Imageability and Other Variables. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psycholinguistic Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;47&lt;/em&gt;(3), 641&amp;ndash;661. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10936-017-9548-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10936-017-9548-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miller, J., Brookie, K., Wales, S., Wallace, S., &amp;amp; Kaup, B. (2018). Embodied cognition: Is activation of the motor cortex essential for understanding action verbs? &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;44&lt;/em&gt;(3), 335&amp;ndash;370. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000451&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000451&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minervino, R. A., Martín, A., Tavernini, L. M., &amp;amp; Trench, M. (2018). The Understanding of Visual Metaphors by the Congenitally Blind. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 1242. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01242&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01242&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moretti, S., &amp;amp; Greco, A. (2018). Truth is in the head. A nod and shake compatibility effect. &lt;em&gt;Acta Psychologica&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;185&lt;/em&gt;, 203&amp;ndash;218. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2018.02.010&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2018.02.010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moretti, S., &amp;amp; Greco, A. (2020). Nodding and shaking of the head as simulated approach and avoidance responses. &lt;em&gt;Acta Psychologica&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;203&lt;/em&gt;, 102988. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2019.102988&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2019.102988&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morucci, P., Bottini, R., &amp;amp; Crepaldi, D. (2019). Augmented Modality Exclusivity Norms for Concrete and Abstract Italian Property Words. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt;(1), 42. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5334/joc.88&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5334/joc.88&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mueller, C. J., White, C. N., &amp;amp; Kuchinke, L. (2017). Electrophysiological correlates of the drift diffusion model in visual word recognition. &lt;em&gt;Human Brain Mapping&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;38&lt;/em&gt;(11), 5616&amp;ndash;5627. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.23753&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.23753&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muraki, E. J., Doyle, A., Protzner, A. B., &amp;amp; Pexman, P. M. (2023). Context matters: How do task demands modulate the recruitment of sensorimotor information during language processing? &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, 976954. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2022.976954&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2022.976954&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muraki, E. J., Speed, L. J., &amp;amp; Pexman, P. M. (2023). Insights into embodied cognition and mental imagery from aphantasia. &lt;em&gt;Nature Reviews Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt;(10), 591&amp;ndash;605. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s44159-023-00221-9&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s44159-023-00221-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okuno, H. Y., &amp;amp; Guedes, G. (2020). Automatic XML creation for Multisensorial Books. &lt;em&gt;2020 XV Conferencia Latinoamericana de Tecnologias de Aprendizaje (LACLO)&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/LACLO50806.2020.9381139&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/LACLO50806.2020.9381139&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ostarek, M., &amp;amp; Vigliocco, G. (2017). Reading sky and seeing a cloud: On the relevance of events for perceptual simulation. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;43&lt;/em&gt;(4), 579&amp;ndash;590. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000318&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000318&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pecher, D. (2018). Curb Your Embodiment. &lt;em&gt;Topics in Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(3), 501&amp;ndash;517. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12311&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12311&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pérez-Gay Juárez, F., Labrecque, D., &amp;amp; Frak, V. (2019). Assessing language-induced motor activity through Event Related Potentials and the Grip Force Sensor, an exploratory study. &lt;em&gt;Brain and Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;135&lt;/em&gt;, 103572. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandc.2019.05.010&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandc.2019.05.010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pérez-Sánchez, M. Á., Stadthagen-Gonzalez, H., Guasch, M., Hinojosa, J. A., Fraga, I., Marín, J., &amp;amp; Ferré, P. (2021). EmoPro &amp;ndash; Emotional prototypicality for 1286 Spanish words: Relationships with affective and psycholinguistic variables. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1857&amp;ndash;1875. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-020-01519-9&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-020-01519-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfecto, H., Galak, J., Simmons, J. P., &amp;amp; Nelson, L. D. (2017). Rejecting a bad option feels like choosing a good one. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;113&lt;/em&gt;(5), 659&amp;ndash;670. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/pspa0000092&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/pspa0000092&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perlman, M., Little, H., Thompson, B., &amp;amp; Thompson, R. L. (2018). Iconicity in Signed and Spoken Vocabulary: A Comparison Between American Sign Language, British Sign Language, English, and Spanish. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 1433. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01433&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01433&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pexman, P. M. (2019). The role of embodiment in conceptual development. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;34&lt;/em&gt;(10), 1274&amp;ndash;1283. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2017.1303522&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2017.1303522&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pexman, P. M., Muraki, E., Sidhu, D. M., Siakaluk, P. D., &amp;amp; Yap, M. J. (2019). Quantifying sensorimotor experience: Body&amp;ndash;object interaction ratings for more than 9,000 English words. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;51&lt;/em&gt;(2), 453&amp;ndash;466. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-018-1171-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-018-1171-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piai, V., &amp;amp; Zheng, X. (2019). Speaking waves: Neuronal oscillations in language production. In &lt;em&gt;Psychology of Learning and Motivation&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 71, pp. 265&amp;ndash;302). Elsevier. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.plm.2019.07.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.plm.2019.07.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plekhanov Russian University of Economics, Simonenko, M. A., Kazaryan, S. Y., &amp;amp; Plekhanov Russian University of Economics. (2023). Synaesthetic metaphor and its reproduction in Russian-to-English translation: A frame-based study. &lt;em&gt;RESEARCH RESULT Theoretical and Applied Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(3). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.18413/2313-8912-2023-9-3-0-2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.18413/2313-8912-2023-9-3-0-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popović Stijačić, M., &amp;amp; Filipović Đurđević, D. (2022). Perceptual richness of words and its role in free and cued recall. &lt;em&gt;Primenjena Psihologija&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(3), 355&amp;ndash;381. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.19090/pp.v15i3.2400&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.19090/pp.v15i3.2400&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulvermüller, F. (2018a). Neural reuse of action perception circuits for language, concepts and communication. &lt;em&gt;Progress in Neurobiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;160&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;44. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2017.07.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2017.07.001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulvermüller, F. (2018b). Neurobiological Mechanisms for Semantic Feature Extraction and Conceptual Flexibility. &lt;em&gt;Topics in Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(3), 590&amp;ndash;620. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12367&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12367&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purves, R. S., Striedl, P., Kong, I., &amp;amp; Majid, A. (2023). Conceptualizing Landscapes Through Language: The Role of Native Language and Expertise in the Representation of Waterbody Related Terms. &lt;em&gt;Topics in Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(3), 560&amp;ndash;583. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12652&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/tops.12652&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radvansky, G. A. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Human Memory&lt;/em&gt; (3rd ed.). Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315542768&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315542768&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radvansky, G. A. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Human Memory&lt;/em&gt; (4th ed.). Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429287039&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429287039&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rahimi, S., Farahibozorg, S.-R., Jackson, R., &amp;amp; Hauk, O. (2022). Task modulation of spatiotemporal dynamics in semantic brain networks: An EEG/MEG study. &lt;em&gt;NeuroImage&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;246&lt;/em&gt;, 118768. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2021.118768&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2021.118768&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raia, R. (2023). An analysis of conceptual ambiguities in the debate on the format of concepts. &lt;em&gt;Phenomenology and the Cognitive Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11097-023-09938-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11097-023-09938-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raj, R., Hörberg, T., Lindroos, R., Larsson, M., Herman, P., Laukka, E. J., &amp;amp; Olofsson, J. K. (2023). Odor identification errors reveal cognitive aspects of age-associated smell loss. &lt;em&gt;Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;236&lt;/em&gt;, 105445. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2023.105445&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2023.105445&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reggin, L. D., Gómez Franco, L. E., Horchak, O. V., Labrecque, D., Lana, N., Rio, L., &amp;amp; Vigliocco, G. (2023). Consensus Paper: Situated and Embodied Language Acquisition. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(1), 63. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5334/joc.308&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5334/joc.308&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repetto, C., Rodella, C., Conca, F., Santi, G. C., &amp;amp; Catricalà, E. (2022). The Italian Sensorimotor Norms: Perception and action strength measures for 959 words. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-022-02004-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-022-02004-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rey, A. E., Riou, B., Vallet, G. T., &amp;amp; Versace, R. (2017). The automatic visual simulation of words: A memory reactivated mask slows down conceptual access. &lt;em&gt;Canadian Journal of Experimental Psychology / Revue Canadienne de Psychologie Expérimentale&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;71&lt;/em&gt;(1), 14&amp;ndash;22. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/cep0000100&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/cep0000100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reymore, L. (2022). Characterizing prototypical musical instrument timbres with timbre trait profiles. &lt;em&gt;Musicae Scientiae&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(3), 648&amp;ndash;674. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/10298649211001523&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/10298649211001523&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinson, M. D., Fetterman, A. K., Meier, B. P., Persich, M. R., &amp;amp; Waters, M. R. (2021). Embodied Perspectives on Personality. In M. D. Robinson &amp;amp; L. E. Thomas (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Embodied Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 477&amp;ndash;498). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-78471-3_21&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-78471-3_21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinson, M. D., &amp;amp; Thomas, L. E. (2021). Introduction to Embodied Psychology: Thinking, Feeling, and Acting. In M. D. Robinson &amp;amp; L. E. Thomas (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Embodied Psychology&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1&amp;ndash;19). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-78471-3_1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-78471-3_1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;San Roque, L., Kendrick, K. H., Norcliffe, E., &amp;amp; Majid, A. (2018). Universal meaning extensions of perception verbs are grounded in interaction. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(3), 371&amp;ndash;406. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/cog-2017-0034&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1515/cog-2017-0034&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scerrati, E., D&#39;Ascenzo, S., Nicoletti, R., Villani, C., &amp;amp; Lugli, L. (2022). Assessing Interpersonal Proximity Evaluation in the COVID-19 Era: Evidence From the Affective Priming Task. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;, 901730. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2022.901730&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2022.901730&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scerrati, E., Iani, C., Lugli, L., Nicoletti, R., &amp;amp; Rubichi, S. (2020). Do my hands prime your hands? The hand-to-response correspondence effect. &lt;em&gt;Acta Psychologica&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;203&lt;/em&gt;, 103012. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2020.103012&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2020.103012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scerrati, E., Iani, C., &amp;amp; Rubichi, S. (2021). Does the Activation of Motor Information Affect Semantic Processing? In L. Bechberger, K.-U. Kühnberger, &amp;amp; M. Liu (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Concepts in Action&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 9, pp. 153&amp;ndash;166). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-69823-2_7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-69823-2_7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scerrati, E., Lugli, L., Nicoletti, R., &amp;amp; Borghi, A. M. (2017). The Multilevel Modality-Switch Effect: What Happens When We See the Bees Buzzing and Hear the Diamonds Glistening. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;24&lt;/em&gt;(3), 798&amp;ndash;803. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-016-1150-2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13423-016-1150-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scherer, D., &amp;amp; Wentura, D. (2018). Combining the Post-Cue Task and the Perceptual Identification Task to Assess Parallel Activation and Mutual Facilitation of Related Primes and Targets. &lt;em&gt;Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;65&lt;/em&gt;(2), 84&amp;ndash;97. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1027/1618-3169/a000396&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1027/1618-3169/a000396&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schilhab, T. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Derived Embodiment in Abstract Language&lt;/em&gt;. Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-56056-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-56056-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schulte Im Walde, S., &amp;amp; Frassinelli, D. (2022). Distributional Measures of Semantic Abstraction. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 796756. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/frai.2021.796756&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/frai.2021.796756&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seghier, M. L. (2023). Multiple functions of the angular gyrus at high temporal resolution. &lt;em&gt;Brain Structure and Function&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;228&lt;/em&gt;(1), 7&amp;ndash;46. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-022-02512-y&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-022-02512-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Šetić Beg, M. (2021). Uloga utjelovljenja u razumijevanju pojmova. &lt;em&gt;Psihologijske Teme&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;30&lt;/em&gt;(2), 371&amp;ndash;395. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31820/pt.30.2.12&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.31820/pt.30.2.12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shen, G., Wang, R., Yang, M., &amp;amp; Xie, J. (2022). Chinese Children with Congenital and Acquired Blindness Represent Concrete Concepts in Vertical Space through Tactile Perception. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(17), 11055. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph191711055&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph191711055&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sidhu, D. M., &amp;amp; Pexman, P. M. (2018). Lonely sensational icons: Semantic neighbourhood density, sensory experience and iconicity. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(1), 25&amp;ndash;31. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2017.1358379&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2017.1358379&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed, L. J., &amp;amp; Brybaert, M. (2022). Dutch sensory modality norms. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;54&lt;/em&gt;(3), 1306&amp;ndash;1318. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-021-01656-9&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-021-01656-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed, L. J., &amp;amp; Majid, A. (2017). Dutch modality exclusivity norms: Simulating perceptual modality in space. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(6), 2204&amp;ndash;2218. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-017-0852-3&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-017-0852-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed, L. J., &amp;amp; Majid, A. (2018). An Exception to Mental Simulation: No Evidence for Embodied Odor Language. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;42&lt;/em&gt;(4), 1146&amp;ndash;1178. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12593&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12593&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed, L. J., &amp;amp; Majid, A. (2020). Grounding language in the neglected senses of touch, taste, and smell. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Neuropsychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;37&lt;/em&gt;(5&amp;ndash;6), 363&amp;ndash;392. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/02643294.2019.1623188&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/02643294.2019.1623188&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed, L. J., Papies, E. K., &amp;amp; Majid, A. (2023). Mental simulation across sensory modalities predicts attractiveness of food concepts. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(3), 557&amp;ndash;571. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/xap0000461&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/xap0000461&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sri-Ganeshan, M. (2021). Modality Effect. In M. Raz &amp;amp; P. Pouryahya (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Decision Making in Emergency Medicine&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 215&amp;ndash;220). Springer Singapore. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-16-0143-9_34&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-16-0143-9_34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strik Lievers, F., &amp;amp; Winter, B. (2018). Sensory language across lexical categories. &lt;em&gt;Lingua&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;204&lt;/em&gt;, 45&amp;ndash;61. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lingua.2017.11.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lingua.2017.11.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Su, C., Wang, X., Wang, Z., &amp;amp; Chen, Y. (2019). A model of synesthetic metaphor interpretation based on cross-modality similarity. &lt;em&gt;Computer Speech &amp;amp; Language&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;58&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;16. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csl.2019.03.003&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csl.2019.03.003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szychowska, M., &amp;amp; Wiens, S. (2021). Visual load effects on the auditory steady-state responses to 20-, 40-, and 80-Hz amplitude-modulated tones. &lt;em&gt;Physiology &amp;amp; Behavior&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;228&lt;/em&gt;, 113240. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physbeh.2020.113240&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physbeh.2020.113240&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tarai, S., Bit, A., Kumar, R., &amp;amp; Savekar, A. (2021). Processing of party symbols and names predicts the results of 2019 Indian parliamentary election: Analysing psycholinguistic behavioural incongruency effects. &lt;em&gt;Psychology of Language and Communication&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;(1), 264&amp;ndash;295. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2478/plc-2021-0012&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2478/plc-2021-0012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tatiya, G., Hosseini, R., Hughes, M. C., &amp;amp; Sinapov, J. (2019). Sensorimotor Cross-Behavior Knowledge Transfer for Grounded Category Recognition. &lt;em&gt;2019 Joint IEEE 9th International Conference on Development and Learning and Epigenetic Robotics (ICDL-EpiRob)&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/DEVLRN.2019.8850715&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/DEVLRN.2019.8850715&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tatiya, G., Hosseini, R., Hughes, M. C., &amp;amp; Sinapov, J. (2020). A Framework for Sensorimotor Cross-Perception and Cross-Behavior Knowledge Transfer for Object Categorization. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Robotics and AI&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;, 522141. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/frobt.2020.522141&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/frobt.2020.522141&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tatiya, G., &amp;amp; Sinapov, J. (2019). Deep Multi-Sensory Object Category Recognition Using Interactive Behavioral Exploration. &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)&lt;/em&gt;, 7872&amp;ndash;7878. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ICRA.2019.8794095&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/ICRA.2019.8794095&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teodorescu, H.-N., &amp;amp; Bolea, S. C. (2019). Text Sectioning based on Stylometric Distances. &lt;em&gt;2019 International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD)&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/SPED.2019.8906616&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/SPED.2019.8906616&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomason, J., Padmakumar, A., Sinapov, J., Walker, N., Jiang, Y., Yedidsion, H., Hart, J., Stone, P., &amp;amp; Mooney, R. (2020). Jointly Improving Parsing and Perception for Natural Language Commands through Human-Robot Dialog. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;67&lt;/em&gt;, 327&amp;ndash;374. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1613/jair.1.11485&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1613/jair.1.11485&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tillman, R., &amp;amp; Louwerse, M. (2018). Estimating Emotions Through Language Statistics and Embodied Cognition. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psycholinguistic Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;47&lt;/em&gt;(1), 159&amp;ndash;167. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10936-017-9522-y&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10936-017-9522-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tjuka, A., Forkel, R., &amp;amp; List, J.-M. (2021). Linking norms, ratings, and relations of words and concepts across multiple language varieties. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;54&lt;/em&gt;(2), 864&amp;ndash;884. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-021-01650-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-021-01650-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomsk State University, Vladimirova, V. E., Rezanova, Z. I., Tomsk State University, Korshunova, I. S., &amp;amp; Tomsk State University. (2022). Ethno-linguistic contact as reflected in language cognition: Does bilingualism affect subjective assessments of perceptual semantics?*. &lt;em&gt;Rusin&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;70&lt;/em&gt;, 214&amp;ndash;231. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.17223/18572685/70/12&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.17223/18572685/70/12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utsumi, A. (2020). Exploring What Is Encoded in Distributional Word Vectors: A Neurobiologically Motivated Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;44&lt;/em&gt;(6), e12844. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12844&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12844&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valenzuela, J. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Meaning in English: An Introduction&lt;/em&gt; (1st ed.). Cambridge University Press. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316156278&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316156278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van De Weijer, J., Bianchi, I., &amp;amp; Paradis, C. (2023). Sensory modality profiles of antonyms. &lt;em&gt;Language and Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;15. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2023.20&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2023.20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vergallito, A., Petilli, M. A., &amp;amp; Marelli, M. (2020). Perceptual modality norms for 1,121 Italian words: A comparison with concreteness and imageability scores and an analysis of their impact in word processing tasks. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;52&lt;/em&gt;(4), 1599&amp;ndash;1616. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01337-8&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01337-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verheyen, S., De Deyne, S., Linsen, S., &amp;amp; Storms, G. (2020). Lexicosemantic, affective, and distributional norms for 1,000 Dutch adjectives. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;52&lt;/em&gt;(3), 1108&amp;ndash;1121. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01303-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-019-01303-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vigliocco, G., Zhang, Y., Del Maschio, N., Todd, R., &amp;amp; Tuomainen, J. (2020). Electrophysiological signatures of English onomatopoeia. &lt;em&gt;Language and Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(1), 15&amp;ndash;35. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.38&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.38&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volfart, A., Rice, G. E., Lambon Ralph, M. A., &amp;amp; Rossion, B. (2021). Implicit, automatic semantic word categorisation in the left occipito-temporal cortex as revealed by fast periodic visual stimulation. &lt;em&gt;NeuroImage&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;238&lt;/em&gt;, 118228. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2021.118228&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2021.118228&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W, D., C, P., C, M.-L., &amp;amp; F, L. (2023). Imagining and reading actions: Towards similar motor representations. &lt;em&gt;Heliyon&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), e13426. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e13426&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e13426&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wajnerman Paz, A. (2018). A Defense of an Amodal Number System. &lt;em&gt;Philosophies&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;(2), 13. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/philosophies3020013&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/philosophies3020013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wajnerman Paz, A. (2019). Using neural response properties to draw the distinction between modal and amodal representations. &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;32&lt;/em&gt;(3), 301&amp;ndash;331. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/09515089.2018.1563677&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/09515089.2018.1563677&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wajnerman-Paz, A., &amp;amp; Rojas-Líbano, D. (2022). On the role of contextual factors in cognitive neuroscience experiments: A mechanistic approach. &lt;em&gt;Synthese&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;200&lt;/em&gt;(5), 402. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11229-022-03870-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11229-022-03870-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wan, M., Su, Q., Ahrens, K., &amp;amp; Huang, C.-R. (2023). Perceptional and actional enrichment for metaphor detection with sensorimotor norms. &lt;em&gt;Natural Language Engineering&lt;/em&gt;, 1&amp;ndash;29. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S135132492300044X&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/S135132492300044X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang, L., Chen, Q., Chen, Y., &amp;amp; Zhong, R. (2019). The Effect of Sweet Taste on Romantic Semantic Processing: An ERP Study. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 1573. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01573&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01573&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang, Y., &amp;amp; Zeng, Y. (2022a). Multisensory Concept Learning Framework Based on Spiking Neural Networks. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, 845177. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsys.2022.845177&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsys.2022.845177&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang, Y., &amp;amp; Zeng, Y. (2022b). Statistical Analysis of Multisensory and Text-Derived Representations on Concept Learning. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, 861265. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fncom.2022.861265&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fncom.2022.861265&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wassenburg, S. I., De Koning, B. B., De Vries, M. H., Boonstra, A. M., &amp;amp; Van Der Schoot, M. (2017). Gender differences in mental simulation during sentence and word processing. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Research in Reading&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;40&lt;/em&gt;(3), 274&amp;ndash;296. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-9817.12066&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-9817.12066&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wentura, D. (2019). Cognition and emotion: On paradigms and metaphors. &lt;em&gt;Cognition and Emotion&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(1), 85&amp;ndash;93. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/02699931.2019.1567464&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/02699931.2019.1567464&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wingfield, C., &amp;amp; Connell, L. (2022a). Sensorimotor distance: A grounded measure of semantic similarity for 800 million concept pairs. &lt;em&gt;Behavior Research Methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;55&lt;/em&gt;(7), 3416&amp;ndash;3432. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-022-01965-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-022-01965-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wingfield, C., &amp;amp; Connell, L. (2022b). Understanding the role of linguistic distributional knowledge in cognition. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;37&lt;/em&gt;(10), 1220&amp;ndash;1270. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2022.2069278&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2022.2069278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, A., Dudschig, C., Miller, J., Ulrich, R., &amp;amp; Kaup, B. (2022). The action-sentence compatibility effect (ACE): Meta-analysis of a benchmark finding for embodiment. &lt;em&gt;Acta Psychologica&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;230&lt;/em&gt;, 103712. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2022.103712&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2022.103712&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, B. (2019). &lt;em&gt;Statistics for Linguists: An Introduction Using R&lt;/em&gt; (1st ed.). Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315165547&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315165547&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, B. (2022). Mapping the landscape of exploratory and confirmatory data analysis in linguistics. In D. Tay &amp;amp; M. X. Pan (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Data Analytics in Cognitive Linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 13&amp;ndash;48). De Gruyter. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/9783110687279-002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1515/9783110687279-002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, B. (2023). Abstract concepts and emotion: Cross-linguistic evidence and arguments against affective embodiment. &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;378&lt;/em&gt;(1870), 20210368. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2021.0368&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2021.0368&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, B., Fischer, M. H., Scheepers, C., &amp;amp; Myachykov, A. (2023). More is Better: English Language Statistics are Biased Toward Addition. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;47&lt;/em&gt;(4), e13254. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.13254&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.13254&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, B., Perlman, M., &amp;amp; Majid, A. (2018). Vision dominates in perceptual language: English sensory vocabulary is optimized for usage. &lt;em&gt;Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;179&lt;/em&gt;, 213&amp;ndash;220. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.05.008&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2018.05.008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, B., Perlman, M., Perry, L. K., &amp;amp; Lupyan, G. (2017). Which words are most iconic?: Iconicity in English sensory words. &lt;em&gt;Interaction Studies. Social Behaviour and Communication in Biological and Artificial Systems&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(3), 443&amp;ndash;464. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/is.18.3.07win&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/is.18.3.07win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, B., Sóskuthy, M., Perlman, M., &amp;amp; Dingemanse, M. (2022). Trilled /r/ is associated with roughness, linking sound and touch across spoken languages. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(1), 1035. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-04311-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-04311-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter, B., &amp;amp; Strik-Lievers, F. (2023). Semantic distance predicts metaphoricity and creativity judgments in synesthetic metaphors. &lt;em&gt;Metaphor and the Social World&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt;(1), 59&amp;ndash;80. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/msw.00029.win&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/msw.00029.win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, C., &amp;amp; Mu, X. (2023). Sensory experience ratings (SERs) for 1,130 Chinese words: Relationships with other semantic and lexical psycholinguistic variables. &lt;em&gt;Linguistics Vanguard&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;0&lt;/em&gt;(0). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/lingvan-2022-0083&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1515/lingvan-2022-0083&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xiong, J., &amp;amp; Huang, C.-R. (2018). Somewhere in COLDNESS Lies Nibbāna: Lexical Manifestations of COLDNESS. In J.-F. Hong, Q. Su, &amp;amp; J.-S. Wu (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Chinese Lexical Semantics&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 11173, pp. 70&amp;ndash;81). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-04015-4_6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-04015-4_6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xu, Y., Vignali, L., Sigismondi, F., Crepaldi, D., Bottini, R., &amp;amp; Collignon, O. (2023). Similar object shape representation encoded in the inferolateral occipitotemporal cortex of sighted and early blind people. &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(7), e3001930. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.3001930&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.3001930&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yan, J., Li, W., Zhang, T., Zhang, J., Jin, Z., &amp;amp; Li, L. (2023). Structural and functional neural substrates underlying the concreteness effect. &lt;em&gt;Brain Structure and Function&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;228&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1493&amp;ndash;1510. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-023-02668-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-023-02668-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yasuda, M., Stins, J. F., &amp;amp; Higuchi, T. (2017). Effect of Constrained Arm Posture on the Processing of Action Verbs. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2017.00057&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2017.00057&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yin Zhong, &amp;amp; Chu-Ren Huang. (2020). Sweetness or Mouthfeel: A corpus-based study of the conceptualization of taste. &lt;em&gt;Linguistic Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;37&lt;/em&gt;(3), 359&amp;ndash;387. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.17250/KHISLI.37.3.202012.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.17250/KHISLI.37.3.202012.001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zappa, A., Mestre, D., Pergandi, J.-M., Bolger, D., &amp;amp; Frenck-Mestre, C. (2022). Cross-linguistic gender congruency effects during lexical access in novice L2 learners: Evidence from ERPs. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;37&lt;/em&gt;(9), 1073&amp;ndash;1098. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2022.2039726&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2022.2039726&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zeng, Y., Zhao, D., Zhao, F., Shen, G., Dong, Y., Lu, E., Zhang, Q., Sun, Y., Liang, Q., Zhao, Y., Zhao, Z., Fang, H., Wang, Y., Li, Y., Liu, X., Du, C., Kong, Q., Ruan, Z., &amp;amp; Bi, W. (2023). BrainCog: A spiking neural network based, brain-inspired cognitive intelligence engine for brain-inspired AI and brain simulation. &lt;em&gt;Patterns&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(8), 100789. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.patter.2023.100789&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.patter.2023.100789&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhang, M., Wu, X., &amp;amp; Wang, A. (2021). Crossmodal Nonspatial Repetition Inhibition Due to Modality Shift. &lt;em&gt;Perception&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;50&lt;/em&gt;(2), 116&amp;ndash;128. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0301006620988209&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0301006620988209&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhang, X., Amiri, S., Sinapov, J., Thomason, J., Stone, P., &amp;amp; Zhang, S. (2023). Multimodal embodied attribute learning by robots for object-centric action policies. &lt;em&gt;Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;47&lt;/em&gt;(5), 505&amp;ndash;528. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10514-023-10098-5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10514-023-10098-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhang, X., Sinapov, J., &amp;amp; Zhang, S. (2021, July 12). Planning Multimodal Exploratory Actions for Online Robot Attribute Learning. &lt;em&gt;Robotics: Science and Systems XVII&lt;/em&gt;. Robotics: Science and Systems 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.15607/RSS.2021.XVII.005&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.15607/RSS.2021.XVII.005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhang, Y., Mirman, D., &amp;amp; Hoffman, P. (2023). Taxonomic and thematic relations rely on different types of semantic features: Evidence from an fMRI meta-analysis and a semantic priming study. &lt;em&gt;Brain and Language&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;242&lt;/em&gt;, 105287. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandl.2023.105287&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandl.2023.105287&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao, Q. (2020a). From Linguistic Synaesthesia to Conceptual Metaphor Theory. In Q. Zhao, &lt;em&gt;Embodied Conceptualization or Neural Realization&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 10, pp. 115&amp;ndash;128). Springer Singapore. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-32-9315-1_7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-32-9315-1_7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao, Q. (2020b). Methodology: A Corpus-Driven Approach. In Q. Zhao, &lt;em&gt;Embodied Conceptualization or Neural Realization&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 10, pp. 19&amp;ndash;34). Springer Singapore. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-32-9315-1_2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-32-9315-1_2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao, Q., Ahrens, K., &amp;amp; Huang, C.-R. (2022). Linguistic synesthesia is metaphorical: A lexical-conceptual account. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(3), 553&amp;ndash;583. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/cog-2021-0098&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1515/cog-2021-0098&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao, Q., Huang, C.-R., &amp;amp; Ahrens, K. (2019). Directionality of linguistic synesthesia in Mandarin: A corpus-based study. &lt;em&gt;Lingua&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;232&lt;/em&gt;, 102744. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lingua.2019.102744&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lingua.2019.102744&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao, Q., &amp;amp; Long, Y. (2022). A Diachronic Study on Linguistic Synesthesia in Chinese. In M. Dong, Y. Gu, &amp;amp; J.-F. Hong (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Chinese Lexical Semantics&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 13250, pp. 84&amp;ndash;94). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-06547-7_6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-06547-7_6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao, Q., Long, Y., &amp;amp; Huang, C.-R. (2020). Linguistic Synaesthesia of Mandarin Sensory Adjectives: Corpus-Based and Experimental Approaches. In J.-F. Hong, Y. Zhang, &amp;amp; P. Liu (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Chinese Lexical Semantics&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 11831, pp. 139&amp;ndash;146). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-38189-9_14&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-38189-9_14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao, T., Huang, Y., Chen, D., Jiao, L., Marmolejo-Ramos, F., Wang, R., &amp;amp; Xie, J. (2020). The modality switching costs of Chinese&amp;ndash;English bilinguals in the processing of L1 and L2. &lt;em&gt;Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;73&lt;/em&gt;(3), 396&amp;ndash;412. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021819878089&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021819878089&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhong, J., Peniak, M., Tani, J., Ogata, T., &amp;amp; Cangelosi, A. (2019). Sensorimotor input as a language generalisation tool: A neurorobotics model for generation and generalisation of noun-verb combinations with sensorimotor inputs. &lt;em&gt;Autonomous Robots&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;43&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1271&amp;ndash;1290. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10514-018-9793-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10514-018-9793-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhong, Y., Huang, C.-R., &amp;amp; Dong, S. (2022). Bodily sensation and embodiment: A corpus-based study of gustatory vocabulary in Mandarin Chinese. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Chinese Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;50&lt;/em&gt;(1), 196&amp;ndash;230. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1353/jcl.2022.0008&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1353/jcl.2022.0008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhong, Y., Wan, M., Ahrens, K., &amp;amp; Huang, C.-R. (2022). Sensorimotor norms for Chinese nouns and their relationship with orthographic and semantic variables. &lt;em&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;37&lt;/em&gt;(8), 1000&amp;ndash;1022. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2022.2035416&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/23273798.2022.2035416&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhu, S., Wang, X., &amp;amp; Liu, P. (2021). Who Killed Sanmao and Virginia Woolf? A Comparative Study of Writers with Suicidal Attempt Based on a Quantitative Linguistic Method. In M. Liu, C. Kit, &amp;amp; Q. Su (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Chinese Lexical Semantics&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 12278, pp. 408&amp;ndash;420). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-81197-6_34&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-81197-6_34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Гарах, Ж. В., Ребрейкина, А. Б., Стрелец, В. Б., Голикова, А. В., &amp;amp; Зайцева, Ю. С. (2019). НЕЙРОФИЗИОЛОГИЧЕСКИЕ МЕХАНИЗМЫ ЧТЕНИЯ. &lt;em&gt;Журнал высшей нервной деятельности им И П Павлова&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;69&lt;/em&gt;(3), 294&amp;ndash;313. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1134/S0044467719030055&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1134/S0044467719030055&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
