<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>syntax | Pablo Bernabeu</title>
    <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/syntax/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/syntax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>syntax</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Pablo Bernabeu, 2015—2024. Licence: [CC BY 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/). Email: pcbernabeu@gmail.com. No cookies operated by this website. Cookies only used by third-party systems such as [Disqus](https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717155-use-of-cookies).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/img/default_preview_image.png</url>
      <title>syntax</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/syntax/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passive constructions and asymmetries between languages</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2024/passive-constructions-and-asymmetries-between-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2024/passive-constructions-and-asymmetries-between-languages/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34; style=&#34;padding-bottom: 0; margin-bottom: 6%;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given all of the data that E&amp;amp;L [Evans and Levinson] cite, how could anyone maintain the notion of a universal grammar with linguistic content? Traditionally, there have been three basic strategies. First, just as we may force English grammar into the Procrustean bed of Latin grammar – that is how I was taught the structure of English in grade school – the grammars of the world’s so-called exotic languages may be forced into an abstract scheme based mainly on European languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;Tomasello (2009)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers often make participants jump through hoops. Due to our personal blind spots, it seems easier to realise the full extent of these acrobatics when we consider the work of other researchers. In linguistic research, the acrobatics are often spurred by unnatural grammatical constructions. For instance, in Spanish, &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-based passive constructions—such as &lt;em&gt;La guerra fue empezada por la tortuga&lt;/em&gt; ‘The war was stated by the turtle’—are much less frequent than in English. This may be due to several characteristics of the passive in Spanish, including the availability of an alternative construction that hinges on the reflexive pronoun &lt;em&gt;se&lt;/em&gt;—e.g., &lt;em&gt;El apartamento se vendió&lt;/em&gt; ‘The apartment was sold’ (Takagaki, 2005). Yet, there is an additional construction available in Spanish (and in other Romance languages) that implements a pronominal object clitic in preverbal position.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/guerra-la-empezo.png&#39; alt=&#39;Comparing the frequency of the English-like passive versus the construction that implements a pronominal object clitic in preverbal position, in Spanish.&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:90%; color: #899499;&#34;&gt;Comparing the frequency of the English-like passive versus the construction that implements a pronominal object clitic in preverbal position.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ratio of 5 to 5,300 speaks for itself. So, it is surprising to find linguistic research that seems overlook the asymmetry between English and Spanish regarding passives. In a study on cross-linguistic syntactic priming in bilingual children, Vasilyeva et al. (2010) used stimuli such as &lt;em&gt;El gato fue lavado por el perro&lt;/em&gt; ‘The cat was washed by the dog’. Through a quick-and-dirty corpus analysis using a search engine, we can examine the limitations of these stimuli. Whereas the English form ‘The cat was washed’ is common enough, the literal translations &lt;em&gt;El gato fue lavado&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;La gata fue lavada&lt;/em&gt; are essentially negligible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/cat-washed.png&#39; alt=&#39;Comparing the frequency of passive constructions in English and in Spanish.&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/gato-lavado.png&#39; alt=&#39;Comparing the frequency of passive constructions in English and in Spanish.&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/gata-lavada.png&#39; alt=&#39;Comparing the frequency of passive constructions in English and in Spanish.&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:90%; color: #899499;&#34;&gt;Comparing the frequency of passive constructions in English and in Spanish.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vasilyeva et al. (2010) observed that, when primed with English-like passives in Spanish, the children increased their use of passive constructions in English. In contrast, exposure to English passives in the prime sentences did not lead to a greater use of the English-like passives in Spanish. The authors described this contrast as an &lt;em&gt;asymmetry&lt;/em&gt;, which has been profusely echoed in the subsequent literature (Serratrice, 2022). The caveat with this finding is that the stimuli themselves contain an asymmetry, as the English-like passive is negligible in Spanish, especially among children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems a good opportunity to reflect on the asymmetries that exist across languages, and on the need to account for those in the creation of stimuli for linguistic studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;references&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serratrice, L. (2022). What can syntactic priming tell us about crosslinguistic influence? In Messenger, K. (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Syntactic priming in language acquisition: Representations, mechanisms and applications&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 129–156). Amsterdam: John Benjamins. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/tilar.31&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/tilar.31&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takagaki, T. (2005). On the productivity of the Spanish passive constructions. In Takagaki et al. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Corpus-based approaches to sentence structures&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 289–309). Amsterdam: John Benjamins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomasello, M. (2009). Universal grammar is dead. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 32&lt;/em&gt;(5), 470–471. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X09990744&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X09990744&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vasilyeva, M., Waterfall, H., Gámez, P. B., Gómez, L. E., Bowers, E., &amp;amp; Shimpi, P. (2010). Cross-linguistic syntactic priming in bilingual children. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Child Language, 37&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1047–1064. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0305000909990213&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0305000909990213&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes footnotes-end-of-document&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a couple of more ideas about pronominal object clitics, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2023/pronominal-object-clitics-in-preverbal-position-are-a-hard-nut-to-crack-for-google-translate&#34;&gt;this other post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pronominal object clitics in preverbal position are a hard nut to crack for Google Translate</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2023/pronominal-object-clitics-in-preverbal-position-are-a-hard-nut-to-crack-for-google-translate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2023/pronominal-object-clitics-in-preverbal-position-are-a-hard-nut-to-crack-for-google-translate/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Unlike English, some Romance languages not only allow—but sometimes require—pronominal object clitics in preverbal position (Hanson &amp;amp; Carlson, 2014; Labotka et al., 2023). That is, instead of saying &lt;em&gt;La maestra ha detto il nome&lt;/em&gt; (Italian) ‘The teacher has said the name’, Italian allows &lt;em&gt;Il nome lo ha detto la maestra&lt;/em&gt; (literally, ‘The name it has said the teacher’), which could translate as ‘The name has been said by the teacher’, ‘&lt;em&gt;The teacher&lt;/em&gt; has said the name’, or even ‘It is the teacher that has said the name’. The form &lt;em&gt;Il nome lo ha detto la maestra&lt;/em&gt; is a marked phrasing that increases the attention to the subject of the sentence. Furthermore, when the clitic is in preverbal position, the degree of focus on the subject is also dependent on the context. For instance, the focus is light in &lt;em&gt;Lo ha detto la maestra&lt;/em&gt;, whereas it is stronger in &lt;em&gt;Lo ha detto la maestra, non l’assistente&lt;/em&gt; “It’s the teacher that’s said it, not the assistant”. Whereas the light case can safely lose the subject-focus in the translation (‘The teacher has said it’), the marked cases would require either a marked pronunciation in speech, or italics in writing (‘&lt;em&gt;The teacher&lt;/em&gt; has said it’), or the idiomatic form ‘The teacher said’, or a marked syntax—for instance, with an it-cleft, as in “It’s the teacher that’s said it, not the assistant”, or by adding ‘oneself’, as in ‘The teacher said it herself’. Now, how does Google Translate (GT) deal with these translations in May 2023? To translate &lt;em&gt;Lo ha detto la maestra&lt;/em&gt;, GT opts for ‘The teacher said’, which is a good, idiomatic option. When it comes to translating to Spanish, GT returns ‘El profesor dijo’, which is the direct equivalent of the English translation (we can ignore the error in the translation of the subject). This option is valid in some varieties of Spanish in America. Nonetheless, it must be noted that a more direct translation from the Italian form would have been very good in Spanish (&lt;em&gt;Lo ha dicho la maestra&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GT has greater trouble when the content of the sentence is slightly less frequent. For instance, &lt;em&gt;Lo cerca la maestra&lt;/em&gt; ‘Him is seeking the teacher’ is stripped of its markedness in GT’s rendering in English—i.e., ‘The teacher is looking for him’. Preserving the subject-focus—e.g., “It’s the teacher that’s looking for him”—would require some syntactic liberties, and hence entail some risks. So, playing it safe is understandable. Our next step is checking the translation to some Romance languages that allow the same movement to preverbal position present in the original Italian sentence &lt;em&gt;Lo cerca la maestra&lt;/em&gt;. Aside from GT, the sentence could be well translated into Romanian as &lt;em&gt;Îl caută dăscăliţa&lt;/em&gt;, or into Spanish as &lt;em&gt;Lo busca la profesora&lt;/em&gt;. In contrast, for both translations, GT returns the equivalents of the English translation—i.e., &lt;em&gt;Profesorul îl caută&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;El profesor lo busca&lt;/em&gt;, again discarding the focus on the subject—unnecessarily in these cases, due to the overlap in the grammars (we can again ignore the errors of lexical gender in the translations).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/Screenshot%202023-05-11%20162627.png&#39; alt=&#39;Suggesting a better translation in Google Translate&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:90%; color: #899499;&#34;&gt;Submitting a better translation is always an option.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fairness, machine translation is an absolute feat overall, provided enough caution is practised. With the expansion of language models, machine translation is only going to improve. So, how much of a piece of cake will it be for GT to crack some of these syntactic details in time, and to preserve syntactic forms across languages when the systems match?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;references&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hanson, A. E. S., &amp;amp; Carlson, M. T. (2014). The roles of first language and proficiency in L2 processing of Spanish clitics: Global effects. &lt;em&gt;Language Learning, 64&lt;/em&gt;(2), 310-342. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/lang.12050&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/lang.12050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labotka, D., Sabo, E., Bonais, R., Gelman, S. A., &amp;amp; Baptista, M. (2023). Testing the effects of congruence in adult multilingual acquisition with implications for creole genesis. &lt;em&gt;Cognition, 235&lt;/em&gt;, 105387. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2023.105387&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2023.105387&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
