<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>syntax | Pablo Bernabeu</title>
    <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/syntax/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/syntax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>syntax</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Pablo Bernabeu, 2015—2024. Licence: [CC BY 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/). Email: pcbernabeu@gmail.com. No cookies operated by this website. Cookies only used by third-party systems such as [Disqus](https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717155-use-of-cookies).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/img/default_preview_image.png</url>
      <title>syntax</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/syntax/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passive constructions and asymmetries between languages</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2024/passive-constructions-and-asymmetries-between-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2024/passive-constructions-and-asymmetries-between-languages/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34; style=&#34;padding-bottom: 0; margin-bottom: 6%;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given all of the data that E&amp;amp;L [Evans &amp;amp; Levinson, 2009] cite, how could anyone maintain the notion of a universal grammar with linguistic content? Traditionally, there have been three basic strategies. First, just as we may force English grammar into the Procrustean bed of Latin grammar – that is how I was taught the structure of English in grade school – the grammars of the world’s so-called exotic languages may be forced into an abstract scheme based mainly on European languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;Tomasello (2009)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers often make participants jump through hoops. Due to our personal blind spots, it seems easier to realise the full extent of these acrobatics when we consider the work of other researchers. In linguistic research, the acrobatics are often spurred by unnatural grammatical constructions. For instance, in Spanish, &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-based passive constructions—such as &lt;em&gt;La guerra fue empezada por …&lt;/em&gt; ‘The war was started by …’—are much less frequent than in English. In Spanish, &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-passives are mostly reserved for the formal, written discourse. Outside of that register, the left-dislocation of the patient is more commonly achieved through the following constructions. One construction hinges on the reflexive pronoun &lt;em&gt;se&lt;/em&gt;—e.g., &lt;em&gt;El apartamento se vendió&lt;/em&gt; ‘The apartment was sold’ (Takagaki, 2005). The other construction implements a pronominal object clitic (usually in preverbal position), as illustrated below.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The latter construction, though not strictly passive, is thematically equivalent to many passives in English (Hidalgo Downing &amp;amp; Downing, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/guerra-la-empezo.png&#39; alt=&#39;Comparing the frequency of the English-like, *be*-based passive to the construction that implements a pronominal object clitic in preverbal position, in Spanish.&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:90%; color: #899499;&#34;&gt;Comparing the frequency of the English-like, &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-based passive to the construction that implements a pronominal object clitic in preverbal position.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ratio of 8 to 5,300 results suggests that &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-passives are much less common than the construction implementing a preverbal clitic. In the light of this ratio, it is surprising to find linguistic research that seems to overlook the asymmetry between English and Spanish regarding passives. For instance, in a study on crosslinguistic syntactic priming in bilingual children, Vasilyeva et al. (2010) used stimuli such as &lt;em&gt;El gato fue lavado por el perro&lt;/em&gt; ‘The cat was washed by the dog’. Through a quick-and-dirty corpus analysis using a search engine, we can examine the limitations of these stimuli. Whereas the English form ‘The cat was washed’ is common enough, the literal translations &lt;em&gt;El gato fue lavado&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;La gata fue lavada&lt;/em&gt; are essentially negligible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/cat-washed.png&#39; alt=&#39;Comparing the frequency of passive constructions in English and in Spanish.&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/gato-lavado.png&#39; alt=&#39;Comparing the frequency of passive constructions in English and in Spanish.&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/gata-lavada.png&#39; alt=&#39;Comparing the frequency of passive constructions in English and in Spanish.&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:90%; color: #899499;&#34;&gt;Comparing the frequency of passive constructions in English and in Spanish.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vasilyeva et al. (2010) observed that, when primed with English-like, &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-based passives in Spanish, the children increased their use of passive constructions in English. In contrast, exposure to English passives in the prime sentences did not lead to a greater use of the English-like passives in Spanish. The authors described this contrast as an &lt;em&gt;asymmetry&lt;/em&gt;, which has been profusely echoed in the subsequent literature on crosslinguistic syntactic priming (Serratrice, 2022). The caveat about this finding is that the stimuli &lt;em&gt;themselves&lt;/em&gt; contained an asymmetry, as the &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-passive is infelicitous in Spanish, certainly when compared to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-passives in English (Hartsuiker &amp;amp; Bernolet, 2017; Vasilyeva et al., 2010), and especially among children, who use passives even less frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntactic isomorphism is less common than it may seem. That is, syntactic structures cannot always be mapped on a one-to-one basis across languages. Even when the same structures exist in two languages, their frequencies may be fundamentally different, as in the case of &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;-based passives in English and Spanish. Thus, where possible, stimuli should capture the functional equivalents between languages, not just the surface-level structural forms, to avoid skewed results. By this means, it will become easier to interpret the results of crosslinguistic priming. At the same time, seeking crosslinguistic overlaps may be like looking for a needle in a haystack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;references&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evans, N., &amp;amp; Levinson, S. C. (2009). The myth of language universals: Language diversity and its importance for cognitive science. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 32&lt;/em&gt;(5), 429-448. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X0999094X&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X0999094X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hartsuiker, R. J., &amp;amp; Bernolet, S. (2017). The development of shared syntax in second language learning. &lt;em&gt;Bilingualism: Language and Cognition, 20&lt;/em&gt;(2), 219-234. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S1366728915000164&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/S1366728915000164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hidalgo Downing, R., &amp;amp; Downing, A. (2012). Topic and topicality in text: A contrastive study of English and Spanish narrative texts. &lt;em&gt;Linguistics and the Human Sciences, 6&lt;/em&gt;, 193–217. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1558/lhs.v6i1-3.193&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1558/lhs.v6i1-3.193&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serratrice, L. (2022). What can syntactic priming tell us about crosslinguistic influence? In Messenger, K. (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Syntactic priming in language acquisition: Representations, mechanisms and applications&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 129–156). Amsterdam: John Benjamins. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/tilar.31&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/tilar.31&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takagaki, T. (2005). On the productivity of the Spanish passive constructions. In Takagaki et al. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Corpus-based approaches to sentence structures&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 289–309). Amsterdam: John Benjamins. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/ubli.2&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/ubli.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomasello, M. (2009). Universal grammar is dead. &lt;em&gt;Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 32&lt;/em&gt;(5), 470–471. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X09990744&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X09990744&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vasilyeva, M., Waterfall, H., Gámez, P. B., Gómez, L. E., Bowers, E., &amp;amp; Shimpi, P. (2010). Cross-linguistic syntactic priming in bilingual children. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Child Language, 37&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1047–1064. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0305000909990213&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0305000909990213&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes footnotes-end-of-document&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a couple of more ideas about pronominal object clitics, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2023/pronominal-object-clitics-in-preverbal-position-are-a-hard-nut-to-crack-for-google-translate&#34;&gt;this other post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pronominal object clitics in preverbal position are a hard nut to crack for Google Translate</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2023/pronominal-object-clitics-in-preverbal-position-are-a-hard-nut-to-crack-for-google-translate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2023/pronominal-object-clitics-in-preverbal-position-are-a-hard-nut-to-crack-for-google-translate/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Unlike English, some Romance languages not only allow—but sometimes require—pronominal object clitics in preverbal position (Hanson &amp;amp; Carlson, 2014; Labotka et al., 2023). That is, instead of saying &lt;em&gt;La maestra ha detto il nome&lt;/em&gt; (Italian) ‘The teacher has said the name’, Italian allows &lt;em&gt;Il nome lo ha detto la maestra&lt;/em&gt; (literally, ‘The name it has said the teacher’), which could translate as ‘The name has been said by the teacher’, ‘&lt;em&gt;The teacher&lt;/em&gt; has said the name’, or even ‘It is the teacher that has said the name’. The form &lt;em&gt;Il nome lo ha detto la maestra&lt;/em&gt; is a marked phrasing that increases the attention to the agent of the action. Furthermore, when the clitic is in preverbal position, the degree of focus on the agent is also dependent on the context. For instance, the focus is light in &lt;em&gt;Lo ha detto la maestra&lt;/em&gt;, whereas it is stronger in &lt;em&gt;Lo ha detto la maestra, non l’assistente&lt;/em&gt; “It’s the teacher that’s said it, not the assistant”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agent-focus can sometimes be relinquished in translations (‘The teacher has said it’). In other cases, it must be preserved by applying an intonational or written emphasis on the agent (‘&lt;em&gt;The teacher&lt;/em&gt; has said it’), or by implementing the idiomatic form ‘The teacher said’, or a marked syntax—for instance, with an it-cleft, as in “It’s the teacher that’s said it”, or by adding ‘oneself’, as in ‘The teacher said it herself’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, how does Google Translate (GT) deal with these translations in May 2023? To translate &lt;em&gt;Lo ha detto la maestra&lt;/em&gt;, GT opts for ‘The teacher said’, which is a good, idiomatic option. When it comes to translating to Spanish, GT returns ‘El profesor dijo’, which is the direct equivalent of the English translation.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This option is valid in some varieties of Spanish in America. Nonetheless, it must be noted that a more direct translation from the Italian form would have been very good in Spanish (&lt;em&gt;Lo ha dicho la maestra&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GT has greater trouble when the content of the sentence is slightly less frequent. For instance, &lt;em&gt;Lo cerca la maestra&lt;/em&gt; ‘Him is seeking the teacher’ is stripped of its markedness in GT’s rendering in English—i.e., ‘The teacher is looking for him’. Preserving the agent-focus—e.g., “It’s the teacher that’s looking for him”—would require some syntactic liberties, and hence entail some risks. So, playing it safe is understandable. Our next step is checking the translation to some Romance languages that allow the same movement to preverbal position present in the original Italian sentence &lt;em&gt;Lo cerca la maestra&lt;/em&gt;. Aside from GT, the sentence could be well translated into Romanian as &lt;em&gt;Îl caută dăscăliţa&lt;/em&gt;, or into Spanish as &lt;em&gt;Lo busca la profesora&lt;/em&gt;. In contrast, for both translations, GT returns the equivalents of the English translation—i.e., &lt;em&gt;Profesorul îl caută&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;El profesor lo busca&lt;/em&gt;, again discarding the focus on the agent—unnecessarily in these cases, due to the overlap in the grammars.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;images/Screenshot%202023-05-11%20162627.png&#39; alt=&#39;Suggesting a better translation in Google Translate&#39; style=&#39;margin-top:2px; margin-bottom:-2px;&#39;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:90%; color: #899499;&#34;&gt;Submitting a better translation is always an option.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fairness, machine translation is an absolute feat overall, provided enough caution is practised. With the expansion of language models, machine translation is only going to improve. So, how much of a piece of cake will it be for GT to crack some of these syntactic details in time, and to preserve syntactic forms across languages when the systems match?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;references&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hanson, A. E. S., &amp;amp; Carlson, M. T. (2014). The roles of first language and proficiency in L2 processing of Spanish clitics: Global effects. &lt;em&gt;Language Learning, 64&lt;/em&gt;(2), 310-342. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/lang.12050&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/lang.12050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labotka, D., Sabo, E., Bonais, R., Gelman, S. A., &amp;amp; Baptista, M. (2023). Testing the effects of congruence in adult multilingual acquisition with implications for creole genesis. &lt;em&gt;Cognition, 235&lt;/em&gt;, 105387. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2023.105387&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2023.105387&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes footnotes-end-of-document&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can again ignore the errors of lexical gender in the translations.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can again ignore the errors of lexical gender in the translations.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
