<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>event-related potentials | Pablo Bernabeu</title>
    <link>/tags/event-related-potentials/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/event-related-potentials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>event-related potentials</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>© Pablo Bernabeu, 2020. [CC BY Attribution licence](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/). Cookies only used by Disqus to enable comments ([see details](https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717155-use-of-cookies)).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/pablobernabeu_image_sharing.png</url>
      <title>event-related potentials</title>
      <link>/tags/event-related-potentials/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-related potentials: Why and how I used them</title>
      <link>/2020/event-related-potentials-why-and-how-i-used-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/event-related-potentials-why-and-how-i-used-them/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Event-related potentials (ERPs) offer a unique insight in the study of human cognition. Let’s look at their reason-to-be for the purposes of research, and how they are defined and processed (this order follows the final relevance of things, although it is chronologically inverse). Most of this content is based on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://psyarxiv.com/5gjvk&#34;&gt;master’s thesis&lt;/a&gt;, which I could fortunately conduct at the Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics, hosted by Dr. Roel Willems, from the Neurobiology of Language Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-are-erps&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are ERPs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERPs are electrical responses in the brain that are elicited by a specific stimulus. They are constantly produced, for every one of our actions. These overlapping electrical pulses happen at extremely high frequencies. Indeed, the signal can be measured once per millisecond. Yeah—picture the electrical 🎆 in your brain. The high frequency of this signal is very interesting for the study of some cognitive processes in particular, for which the time course is (or may be) critical. One such example is conceptual processing—that is, how people understand the meaning of words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;time-course-of-word-processing&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time course of word processing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processing a word takes slightly less than a second—around 800 milliseconds (ms). Within this period, earlier processes (compared to later ones) have been ascribed greater relevance to the core process of understanding a word (Mahon &amp;amp; Caramazza, 2008). This assumes that broader processes start only after more immediate ones have started (but see Lebois, Wilson‐Mendenhall &amp;amp; Barsalou, 2014). The most immediate process is the recognition of a string of letters, which seems to start within 90 ms post word onset in early auditory cortex and the Visual Word Form Area (Willems, Frank, Nijhoff, Hagoort, &amp;amp; van den Bosch, 2016). Then ensue further, fundamental stages known as &lt;em&gt;lexical&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;semantic&lt;/em&gt; processes. Lexical processing is the identification of a string of letters as a known word, and it happens within around 160 ms post word onset. Next, at around 200 ms, we may see the beginning of semantic processing, which denotes a further step in the cognitive analysis of the word that is akin to &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; (Hauk, 2016). These processes may overlap, as indeed suggested by the sensitivity of the N400 ERP (see also next section) to both lexical and semantic tasks (Kutas &amp;amp; Federmeier, 2011). Both processes also likely extend further in the processing timeline (Hauk, 2016). Nonetheless, lexical processing is still generally accepted as a precursor of sorts to semantic processing. One of the reasons why this is important to psycholinguists is that lexical and semantic processing have been differentially linked to certain cognitive phenomena. For instance, tasks promoting semantic processing (e.g., semantic decision, whereby participants describe words as concrete or abstract) have been found to engage sensorimotor simulation of the word’s meaning (known as &lt;em&gt;embodiment&lt;/em&gt;) more strongly than lexical tasks do (Connell &amp;amp; Lynott, 2013; Sato, Mengarelli, Riggio, Gallese, &amp;amp; Buccino, 2008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the lexical and semantic stages have emerged, post-lexical, post-semantic processes follow (Mahon &amp;amp; Caramazza, 2008). These are mental imagery and episodic memory processes—both with an approximate emergence around 270 ms after word onset. The gradual progression from the identification of a word up to accessing its broadest meaning is an important anchoring point in the current research on the alleged embodiment of meaning comprehension, even if we might hope to count on more definitive threshold points (Hauk, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word processing data are mainly based on written word processing, but spoken words are processed quite similarly, if slightly faster (Leonard, Baud, Sjerps, &amp;amp; Chang, 2016; Pulvermüller, Shtyrov, &amp;amp; Ilmoniemi, 2005; Shtyrov, Hauk, &amp;amp; Pulvermüller, 2004).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bigger take-home messages would be: (1) the processing of meaning might only start at around 160 ms post word onset, and (2) processes outside of meaning comprehension might only start at around 270 ms. These working references must be taken with some caution because particular semantic effects have been found at different stages (e.g., the conceptual modality switch, as in Hald, Marshall, Janssen, &amp;amp; Garnham, 2011; Collins, Pecher, Zeelenberg, &amp;amp; Coulson, 2011). Indeed, in an influential critique of blooming findings on embodiment, Mahon and Caramazza (2008) argued that even early effects might possibly be explained in terms of non-embodied processing. They contended that working memory processes that were ancillary rather than semantic could be quickly engaged with the function of ‘colouring’ a concept, not building it up. To further complicate the matter, we do not have absolute certainty on the later section of the time course. Thus, as Hauk (2016) reviews, the different stages likely overlap at certain points, with different degrees of relevance. For instance, lexical processing may continue even once semantic processing has started, but would naturally become less relevant. Indeed, the relation among these processes is likely more of a continuum than a set of clear-cut modules. In a nutshell, the time course is important with some experimental effects in word processing, and, to that extent, we depend on our knowledge of the basic time course of word processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-conceptual-modality-switch-paradigm-and-its-time-course&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The conceptual modality switch paradigm and its time course&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In demonstrating the relevance of embodied cognition, a sizeable series of studies have shown that reading about different conceptual modalities (e.g., auditory ‘loud bell’ followed by visual ‘pink background’) incurs processing costs (Pecher, Zeelenberg, &amp;amp; Barsalou, 2003). Importantly, this manipulation does not concern the presentation mode of the stimulus, maintained constant, but the intrinsic semantic modality of the stimulus concepts. The conceptual modality switch effect has often been replicated (Pecher, Zeelenberg, &amp;amp; Barsalou, 2004; Solomon &amp;amp; Barsalou, 2004; Marques, 2006; Vermeulen, Niedenthal, &amp;amp; Luminet, 2007; van Dantzig, Pecher, Zeelenberg, &amp;amp; Barsalou, 2008; Lynott &amp;amp; Connell, 2009; Ambrosi, Kalenine, Blaye, &amp;amp; Bonthoux, 2011; Collins et al., 2011; Hald et al., 2011; Hald et al., 2013; Scerrati et al., 2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, Willems and Louwerse (2017) addressed a caveat with the time course of the conceptual modality switch paradigm. In previous experiments, trials presented a concept word followed by a property word. ERPs were time-locked to the latter property word. This design may have left uncontrolled a switch produced already at the concept. Indeed, the property word was already supposed to be in the particular modality of the trial. That pitfall could have had two consequences: loss of power and loss of certainty on the time course of the effect. Thus, Bernabeu et al. created a design in which ERPs were time-locked to the first word in target trials (see some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/post/Conceptual_modality_switch_effect_measured_at_first_word&#34;&gt;early input from researchers online&lt;/a&gt;). The purpose of this relocation was not to completely annul the possibility of post-core sensory processes, but to increase the time accuracy by measuring the modality switch from the point at which it is elicited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../post/event-related-potentials/index_files/designoverview.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing this design had an ancillary effect on the measurement of response times. A psycholinguistic experiment like this one requires controlling fundamental variables such as word frequency and length, by matching the means of these variables across experimental conditions. This must be controlled in the target words at least. As it is often the case, this control was only possible in the target words—the first one in target trials—, but it was not possible in the second word, which is the crucial one for response times. Response times could still be measured, but comparisons across conditions were not fully warranted. In sum, this was an ERP design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;erp-components&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ERP components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the ERP signal is plotted, it displays multiple wave shapes, or &lt;em&gt;waveforms&lt;/em&gt;, each with a peak flanked by falling tails. Each of these waves often corresponds to an ERP component, which is what cognitive scientists are often interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple components are known, each having been found to consistently peak around specific points in time during a cognitive process. The peak is one of several features characterising each component. A sketch list is shown below (van Hell &amp;amp; Kroll, 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polarity:&lt;/strong&gt; The component either peaks in the positive or the negative pole of the signal. This polarity is relative to the &lt;em&gt;baseline&lt;/em&gt; point that is created in the preprocessing stage (see below);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;latency:&lt;/strong&gt; the time course of the component, encompassing an onset, a peak and an overall duration;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amplitude:&lt;/strong&gt; the voltage reached at a given time or for a given period;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;topographic scalp distribution:&lt;/strong&gt; the areas in the scalp (the scalp being a reasonable proxy for the brain) in which the component appears;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;functional role:&lt;/strong&gt; the cognitive functions that have been consistently associated with the component.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of components in language processing include the N400, consistently linked to semantic processing, that is, seeking the meaning of words or sentences. The N400 is characterised by a large, negative amplitude peaking at around 400 ms post word onset, primarily found in central and posterior sites. N400 &lt;em&gt;effects&lt;/em&gt;, which are comparisons of the N400 component in different experimental conditions, have consistently appeared under violations of semantic expectations, i.e., related to meaning and events (Kutas &amp;amp; Federmeier, 2011; Swaab, Ledoux, Camblin, &amp;amp; Boudewyn, 2012). Another well-known component in language is the P600, linked to syntactic processing, that is, the structure of sentences (Swaab et al., 2012). Other examples of components include lateralized readiness potentials, signalling motor preparation (Mordkoff &amp;amp; Gianaros, 2000), and the P3b component, which appears in the context of responses (van Vliet et al., 2014). Both the latter are relevant to researchers across domains, who often ward off contamination from these components in their experiments. In Bernabeu et al.’s experiment, for instance, time-locking ERPs to the first word in target trials was also useful to ward off contamination from these components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERP data sets are large, being the product of the number of electrodes times the number of time points times the experimental conditions times the number participants. In recent studies, the number of trials often adds to that product, whereas in previous experiments, the trials tended to be aggregated in each condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;electroencephalography-montage&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Electroencephalography montage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electroencephalography (EEG) montage is an important factor. The options are broadly characterised by three parameters of the electrodes (also called channels).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 30px; line-height: 1.2; padding-bottom: 12px; padding-left: 15px; float: right; display: block;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../../post/event-related-potentials/index_files/EEG MPI open day photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pablo Bernabeu, 2015&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; style=&#39;padding-bottom: 15px; margin-bottom: 0px;&#39; /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: small; padding-left: 5px; padding-top: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;Brainwaves exposed for an open day.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number:&lt;/strong&gt; Traditionally, montages with 32, 64 or 128 electrodes have been used. The larger the number, the higher the spatial resolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wet / dry:&lt;/strong&gt; In some montages, the electrical conductance on the electrodes’ contact point must be increased using some fluid solutions, such as a specific gel (often commercialised by the companies that also make EEG apparatuses). Conversely, dry montages do not need that. Ensuring the proper conductance in wet montages has traditionally been very time-consuming for experimenters, often taking over half an hour of wiggling a blunt syringe distributing the saline solution around the electrodes. Traditionally, wet montages produced more reliable data than dry ones, but &lt;em&gt;the times they are a’changing&lt;/em&gt; (di Flumeri, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active / passive:&lt;/strong&gt; In some wet montages, the conductance job is much facilitated by a pilot light on top of each electrode signalling the conductance level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An EEG/ERP experiment is time-consuming. The preparation (especially conductance-prompting with wet montages) and post-experiment procedures (especially washing the EEG cap) normally take twice or three times as long as the experiment proper. The specific duration of these procedures are especially long for higher-density, wet, passive montages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;preprocessing-erps&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preprocessing ERPs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERPs are not the first signal collected in experiments. They are obtained after considerable, systematic preprocessing of the EEG signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.researchgate.net/post/EEG_error_datasets_missing_channels_Its_strange_because_they_were_recorded_well_and_faulty_files_are_quite_as_heavy_as_the_good_ones_Any_ideas&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Nikolay_Novitskiy/post/EEG_error_datasets_missing_channels_Its_strange_because_they_were_recorded_well_and_faulty_files_are_quite_as_heavy_as_the_good_ones_Any_ideas/attachment/59d6391b79197b8077996520/AS%3A400433085468672%401472482095219/image/41_64ch.png&#34; alt=&#34;Brain Vision waveforms&#34; width=&#39;70%&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Bernabeu et al. study, I used Brain Vision software, and followed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://erpinfo.org/resources&#34;&gt;tutorials from the well-known ERP Boot Camp&lt;/a&gt; of Steve Luck and Emily Kappenman. I applied the following pipeline separately for each participant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;labeling channels (64 electrodes);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;creating channel groups (anterior and posterior);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;re-referencing the signal offline to the right mastoid (RM), having referenced online to the left mastoid (Ref);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../post/event-related-potentials/index_files/EEG%20montage.png&#34; style=&#34;width:90.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;separating my three experimental conditions;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;ocular correction for blinks and significant, vertical or horizontal movements of the eyes (seminal method by Gratton, Coles, &amp;amp; Donchin, 1983, which is the default in Brain Vision);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;baseline correction, which is a standardisation based on a certain period immediately before the onset of the target manipulation;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;further correction of artifacts such as motor action potentials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pipeline is reflected in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/98fs6/&#34;&gt;scripts exported from Brain Vision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &amp;lt;Nodes&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch/OcularCorrection&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif/minave_TotalMatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch/OcularCorrection&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/EmbodiedMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif/minave_EmbodiedMismatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch/OcularCorrection&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;1/Raw Data/labels/positions/rerefRM/TotalMismatch/OcularCorrection/baselinecorr/baselinecorr_artif/minave_TotalMismatch&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/Nodes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word reading ERPs can look somewhat like this after the preprocessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../post/event-related-potentials/index_files/Four%20main%20waveform%20plots%20stacked.png&#34; style=&#34;width:80.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To visualise these waveforms throughout the different sections of the data, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mybinder.org/v2/gh/pablobernabeu/Modality-switch-effects-emerge-early-and-increase-throughout-conceptual-processing/master?urlpath=shiny/Shiny-app/&#34;&gt;dashboard is available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;statistical-analysis&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Statistical analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the myriad repeated measures involved in EEG, linear mixed-effects models are a good option, allowing the registration of electrodes and time points in the error term per participant (and trial, too, if these are not aggregated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conclusion&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event-related potentials fulfil an important role in cognitive neuroscience and psychology, only matched by magnetic electroencephalography (MEG), which unites high temporal and spatial resolution. Learning how to use this method is demanding but even more rewarding. It certainly does not make for fast science, but allows the measurement of experimental effects online, that is, as they unfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn about and overcome multiple challenges. One of the issues I faced once regarded some channels (electrodes) that appeared to be missing from the data. I posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/post/EEG_error_datasets_missing_channels_Its_strange_because_they_were_recorded_well_and_faulty_files_are_quite_as_heavy_as_the_good_ones_Any_ideas&#34;&gt;question on ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt;, and emailed Brain Products, the maker of Brain Vision Recorder, which I was using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could please give me a hand with this error, I would be very grateful. I have EEG from a psychological experiment, recorded with BrainVision Recorder, and being analyzed with BrainVision Analyzer 2. Most of the recordings are perfectly fine, but a few present a big error. Out of 64 original electrodes, only two appear. These are the right mastoid (RM) and the left eye sensor (LEOG). Both are bipolar electrodes. RM is to be re-referenced to the online reference electrode, while LEOG is to be re-referenced to the right eye electrode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just can’t fathom the error because all electrodes worked fine during the recording. Also, the data sets with the error are quite as heavy in terms of bytes as those without the error. Further, why should the RM and LEOG channels remain perfectly well as they do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue might seem like a simple zoom I’ve bypassed, or similar… But unfortunately the channels are just not there. I’ve confirmed it as I tried to copy the pipeline from the good data sets onto the faulty ones, where I got the error ‘No channels enabled.’ In case you had access to the BVA analysis software, please find the raw files for one of the faulty data sets here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to invaluable help from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/post/EEG_error_datasets_missing_channels_Its_strange_because_they_were_recorded_well_and_faulty_files_are_quite_as_heavy_as_the_good_ones_Any_ideas&#34;&gt;ResearchGate contributor&lt;/a&gt; and the Brain Products team, I could put the pieces back together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: Problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Nikolay said, the error originated in Recorder (I had used the workspace from the previous experimenter), and the problem was solved by setting the label and position of each channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried editing the .vhdr file in raw (it seemed nice and quick to directly assign the channel names as labels) but i didn’t quite find the way. Therefore, with a tip from the Brain Products team, I went about it within the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I used the transform function ‘Edit channels’ to rename all labels and set each within their coordinates. I did that for just one subject (it doesn’t take as long as it sounds). Afterwards, I created a ‘History template’ out of that process, and copied it to all other nodes.
At any rate, never getting out of the comfort workspace again… :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;references&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-indent:-2em; margin-left:2em;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambrosi, S., Kalenine, S., Blaye, A., &amp;amp; Bonthoux, F. (2011). Modality switching cost during property verification by 7 years of age. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Behavioral Development, 35&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 78-83.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, P., Willems, R. M., &amp;amp; Louwerse, M. M. (2017). Modality switch effects emerge early and increase throughout conceptual processing: evidence from ERPs. In G. Gunzelmann, A. Howes, T. Tenbrink, &amp;amp; E. J. Davelaar (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1629-1634). Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindmodeling.org/cogsci2017/papers/0318/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://mindmodeling.org/cogsci2017/papers/0318/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collins, J., Pecher, D., Zeelenberg, R., &amp;amp; Coulson, S. (2011). Modality switching in a property verification task: an ERP study of what happens when candles flicker after high heels click. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connell, L., &amp;amp; Lynott, D. (2013). Flexible and fast: Linguistic shortcut affects both shallow and deep conceptual processing. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 20&lt;/em&gt;, 542-550.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di Flumeri, G., Aricò, P., Borghini, G., Sciaraffa, N., Di Florio, A., &amp;amp; Babiloni, F. (2019). The Dry Revolution: Evaluation of Three Different EEG Dry Electrode Types in Terms of Signal Spectral Features, Mental States Classification and Usability. &lt;em&gt;Sensors (Basel, Switzerland), 19&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1365. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/s19061365&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/s19061365&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gratton, G., Coles, M. G., &amp;amp; Donchin, E. (1983). A new method for offline removal of ocular artefact. &lt;em&gt;Electroencephalography and Clinical Neurophysiology, 55&lt;/em&gt;, 4, 468-484.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hald, L. A., Hocking, I., Vernon, D., Marshall, J.-A., &amp;amp; Garnham, A. (2013). Exploring modality switching effects in negated sentences: further evidence for grounded representations. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 4&lt;/em&gt;, 93.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hald, L. A., Marshall, J.-A., Janssen, D. P., &amp;amp; Garnham, A. (2011). Switching modalities in a sentence verification task: ERP evidence for embodied language processing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hauk, O. (2016). Only time will tell—Why temporal information is essential for our neuroscientific understanding of semantics. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 23&lt;/em&gt;, 4, 1072-1079.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kutas, M., &amp;amp; Federmeier, K. D. (2011). Thirty years and counting: finding meaning in the N400 component of the event-related brain potential (ERP). &lt;em&gt;Annual Review of Psychology, 62&lt;/em&gt;, 621–647.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lebois, L. A. M., Wilson-Mendenhall, C. D., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. W. (2014). Are automatic conceptual cores the gold standard of semantic processing? The context-dependence of spatial meaning in grounded congruency effects. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science, 39&lt;/em&gt;, 8, 1764-801.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leonard, M. K., Baud, M. O., Sjerps, M. J., &amp;amp; Chang, E. F. (2016). Perceptual restoration of masked speech in human cortex. &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications, 7&lt;/em&gt;, 13619.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mahon, B.Z., &amp;amp; Caramazza, A. (2008). A critical look at the Embodied Cognition Hypothesis and a new proposal for grounding conceptual content. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Physiology - Paris, 102&lt;/em&gt;, 59-70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marques, J. F. (2006). Specialization and semantic organization: Evidence for multiple semantics linked to sensory modalities. **Memory &amp;amp; Cognition, 34*, 1, 60-67.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mordkoff, J. T., &amp;amp; Gianaros, P. J. (2000). Detecting the onset of the lateralized readiness potential: A comparison of available methods and procedures. &lt;em&gt;Psychophysiology, 37&lt;/em&gt;(3), 347–360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pecher, D., Zeelenberg, R., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. W. (2003). Verifying different-modality properties for concepts produces switching costs. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science, 14&lt;/em&gt;, 2, 119-24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ (2004). Sensorimotor simulations underlie conceptual representations: Modality-specific effects of prior activation. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 11&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 164-167.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulvermüller, F., Shtyrov, Y., &amp;amp; Hauk, O. (2009). Understanding in an instant: Neurophysiological evidence for mechanistic language circuits in the brain. &lt;em&gt;Brain and Language, 110&lt;/em&gt;, 2, 81–94.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sato, M., Mengarelli, M., Riggio, L., Gallese, V., &amp;amp; Buccino, G. (2008). Task related modulation of the motor system during language processing. &lt;em&gt;Brain and Language, 105&lt;/em&gt;, 83–90.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scerrati, E., Baroni, G., Borghi, A. M., Galatolo, R., Lugli, L., &amp;amp; Nicoletti, R. (2015). The modality-switch effect: visually and aurally presented prime sentences activate our senses. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 6&lt;/em&gt;, 1668.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shtyrov, Y., Hauk, O., &amp;amp; Pulvermüller, F. (2004). Distributed neuronal networks for encoding category-specific semantic information: the mismatch negativity to action words. &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Neuroscience, 1&lt;/em&gt;, 4, 1083–1092.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solomon, K. O., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. W. (2004). Perceptual simulation in property verification. &lt;em&gt;Memory &amp;amp; Cognition, 32&lt;/em&gt;, 244-259.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swaab, T.Y., Ledoux, K., Camblin, C.C., &amp;amp; Boudewyn, M.A. (2012) Language related ERP components. (Book Chapter). In Luck, S. J. &amp;amp; Kappenman, E.S. (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Oxford Handbook of Event-Related Potential Components&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 397-440). New York: Oxford University Press&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Dantzig, S., Pecher, D., Zeelenberg, R., &amp;amp; Barsalou, L. W. (2008). Perceptual processing affects conceptual processing. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science, 32&lt;/em&gt;, 579–590.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Hell, J. G., &amp;amp; Kroll, J. F. (2013). Using electrophysiological measures to track the mapping of words to concepts in the bilingual brain: a focus on translation. In J. Altarriba &amp;amp; L. Isurin (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Memory, Language, and Bilingualism: Theoretical and Applied Approaches&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 126-160). New York: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Vliet, M., Manyakov, N., Storms, G., Fias, W., Wiersema, J., &amp;amp; Van Hulle, M. (2014). Response-Related Potentials during semantic priming: the effect of a speeded button response task on ERPs. &lt;em&gt;PLoS One, 9&lt;/em&gt;, 2, e87650.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vermeulen, N., Niedenthal, P. M., &amp;amp; Luminet, O. (2007). Switching between sensory and affective systems incurs processing costs. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science, 31&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 183-192.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willems, R. M., Frank, S. L., Nijhoff, A. D., Hagoort, P., &amp;amp; Van den Bosch, A. (2016). Prediction during natural language comprehension. &lt;em&gt;Cerebral Cortex, 26&lt;/em&gt;, 6, 2506-2516.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating object orientation effects across 14 languages</title>
      <link>/publication/chen-etal-inprep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/chen-etal-inprep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;nbsp-i-classfas-fa-eyeinbsp-a-hrefhttpsosfioh36wrvideo-demonstration-of-the-procedure-followed-in-our-laba&#34;&gt;  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-eye&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;a href=&#39;https://osf.io/h36wr/&#39;&gt;Video demonstration of the procedure followed in our lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div style = &#34;text-indent:-2em; margin-left:2em;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen, S., Szabelska, A., Chartier, C. R., Kekecs, Z., Lynott, D., Bernabeu, P., … Schmidt, K. (conditionally accepted). Investigating object orientation effects across 14 languages. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin and Review&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/t2pjv/&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/t2pjv/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modality switch effects emerge early and increase throughout conceptual processing: evidence from ERPs [Blog]</title>
      <link>/2017/modality-switch-effects-emerge-early-and-increase-throughout-conceptual-processing-evidence-from-erps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2017/modality-switch-effects-emerge-early-and-increase-throughout-conceptual-processing-evidence-from-erps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research has extensively investigated whether conceptual processing is modality-specific—that is, whether meaning is processed to a large extent on the basis of perceptual and motor affordances (Barsalou, 2016). This possibility challenges long-established theories. It suggests a strong link between physical experience and language which is not borne out of the paradigmatic arbitrariness of words (see Lockwood, Dingemanse, &amp;amp; Hagoort, 2016). Modality-specificity also clashes with models of language that have no link to sensory and motor systems (Barsalou, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;https://psyarxiv.com/a5pcz/download&#39;&gt;
      &lt;button style = &#34;background-color: white; color: black; border: 2px solid #4CAF50; border-radius: 12px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h3 style = &#34;margin-top: 7px !important; margin-left: 9px !important; margin-right: 9px !important;&#34;&gt; 
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#DBE6DA;&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-mouse-pointer&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; Article &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp; 
&lt;a href=&#39;https://psyarxiv.com/5gjvk/download&#39;&gt;
      &lt;button style = &#34;background-color: white; color: black; border: 2px solid #196F27; border-radius: 12px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h3 style = &#34;margin-top: 7px !important; margin-left: 9px !important; margin-right: 9px !important;&#34;&gt; 
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#DBE6DA;&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-mouse-pointer&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; Thesis &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/post/Conceptual_modality_switch_effect_measured_at_first_word&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Early discussion on ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/97unm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data and code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mybinder.org/v2/gh/pablobernabeu/Modality-switch-effects-emerge-early-and-increase-throughout-conceptual-processing/master?urlpath=rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;analysis environment in RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Conceptual Modality Switch (CMS) paradigm, participants perform a property verification task, deciding whether certain property words can reasonably describe concept words. Covertly, the conceptual modality of consecutive trials is manipulated in order to produce specific switches in conceptual modality. For instance, after the trial &lt;em&gt;Soundless Answer&lt;/em&gt;, which is primarily auditory, the following trial may match in modality—&lt;em&gt;Loud Welcome&lt;/em&gt;—or mismatch—&lt;em&gt;Fine Selection&lt;/em&gt; (visual).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;designoverview.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modality switches incur processing costs, as reflected in brain signals linked to semantic violation, and in longer response times (RTs) (Scerrati, Lugli, Nicoletti, &amp;amp; Borghi, 2016). This effect suggests that perceptual features of concepts are accessed during conceptual processing. More recently, however, the CMS effect was reanalysed using a non-perceptual alternative. Louwerse and Connell (2011) found that language statistics (the co-occurrence of words in a language) were able to approximately predict visual/haptic, olfactory/gustatory, and auditory modalities, but not the subtler differences between visual and haptic and between olfactory and gustatory, which seemed to be reserved for perceptual simulations. Moreover, faster response times (RTs) were best explained by language statistics, whereas slower RTs were best explained by perceptual simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time course of word processing is important. Research suggests that word processing spans one second, during which different processes—semantic and post-semantic—gradually accumulate (Hauk, 2016). The later an effect, the more reasons to question it. Yet, having an early emergence does not either make an effect lexicosemantic, as the meaning encoded could have gone through working memory before activating the actual system of interest, e.g., sensorimotor (Mahon &amp;amp; Caramazza, 2008). Research also suggests that modal systems may contribute to conceptual processing early on—within 200 ms (Vukovic, Feurra, Shpektor, Myachykov, &amp;amp; Shtyrov, 2017). Thus, measuring effects online may prove valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;experiment&#34;&gt;Experiment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, Willems and Louwerse (2017) investigated whether CMS reflects a functionally relevant process of simulation or instead arises only after basic conceptual processing has been attained. We also examined whether different processing systems, amodal and modal, may compatibly operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We measured CMS online by time-locking Event-Related brain Potentials (ERPs) to the onset of the first word in the target trials, in order to assess how strongly CMS may be influenced by post-semantic processes. Previous research would predict an increase in the CMS effect over time because earlier processing is relatively amodal (Louwerse &amp;amp; Hutchinson, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tested the compatibility of amodal and modal processing by drawing on Louwerse and Connell’s (2011) findings. In this conceptual replication, we split participants into a Quick and a Slow group based on RT. Maintaining CMS as a within-subjects factor, we predicted that the larger modality switches (e.g., auditory to visual) would be picked up equally by both groups, whereas the subtler switches (e.g., haptic to visual) would be picked up only—or more clearly—by the Slow group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stimuli were normed (Bernabeu, Louwerse, &amp;amp; Willems, in prep.). Three CMS conditions were created—Auditory-to-visual, Haptic-to-visual, Visual-to-visual—, each with 36 target trials. The property verification task was pretested valid (&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 19).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All participants but one responded correctly to over half of the trials, with an overall accuracy of 63%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERPs showed a CMS effect from time window 1 on, larger after 350 ms. It appeared with both switch conditions, and was characterized by a more negative amplitude for the switch conditions compared to the no-switch condition. It was generally stronger in the posterior brain regions, and in the Slow group. The results are illustrated in the figure below, which includes 95% Confidence Intervals and time windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;stackERPs.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style = &#34;float: right; margin-left: 30px;&#34; width = &#39;50%&#39; src=&#39;results.jpg&#39; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis was done with Linear Mixed Effects models. Final models presented good fits, with R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; ranging from .748 to .862. First, the CMS effect in time window 1 was confirmed significant. Such an early emergence is unprecedented in the CMS literature, and it may have been enabled by the time-locking of ERPs to the first word in target trials. In this time window, the only process not lexicosemantic is possibly working memory (Hauk, 2016), and therefore this early emergence adds support to the possibility that CMS was directly caused by perceptual simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas, in time window 1, the effect was circumscribed to an interaction with Brain Area, by time window 2 a main effect of CMS emerged, and in windows 3 and 4 the only critical effect was CMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonferroni-corrected, planned ANOVA contrasts into CMS conditions revealed that the no-switch condition differed significantly from the switch conditions. By contrast, the switch conditions (Haptic-to-visual and Auditory-to-visual) hardly differed from each other, underscoring the CMS effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the interaction of Group and CMS was only significant in time windows 1 and 2, windows 2 to 4 presented a pattern fitting our predictions (Louwerse &amp;amp; Connell, 2011). While the Slow group picked up the switches across all modalities similarly, the Quick group picked up the Auditory-to-visual switch more clearly than the Haptic-to-visual switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results broadly suggest that cognition may operate on qualitatively different systems for the same task. In conceptual processing, one of these systems appears to be modality-independent, potentially based on linguistic co-occurrences, whereas another system is modality-specific, linked to physical experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bonus-a-conference-poster-with-further-analyses-nbspa-hrefhttpsmfrosfiorenderurlhttpsosfiodj52ndirect26moderender26actiondownload26moderenderi-classfas-fa-external-link-altia&#34;&gt;Bonus: a conference poster with further analyses  &lt;a href=&#39;https://mfr.osf.io/render?url=https://osf.io/dj52n/?direct%26mode=render%26action=download%26mode=render&#39;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-external-link-alt&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;style&gt;.embed-responsive{position:relative;height:100%;}.embed-responsive iframe{position:absolute;height:100%;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;script&gt;window.jQuery || document.write(&#39;&lt;script src=&#34;//code.jquery.com/jquery-1.11.2.min.js&#34;&gt;\x3C/script&gt;&#39;) &lt;/script&gt;&lt;link href=&#34;https://mfr.osf.io/static/css/mfr.css&#34; media=&#34;all&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34;&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;mfrIframe&#34; class=&#34;mfr mfr-file&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://mfr.osf.io/static/js/mfr.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;script&gt;var mfrRender = new mfr.Render(&#34;mfrIframe&#34;, &#34;https://mfr.osf.io/render?url=https://osf.io/dj52n/?direct%26mode=render%26action=download%26mode=render&#34;);&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div style = &#34;text-indent:-2em; margin-left:2em;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barsalou, L. W. (2016). On staying grounded and avoiding quixotic dead ends. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 23&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, P., Louwerse, M. M., &amp;amp; Willems, R. M. (in prep.). Modality exclusivity norms for 747 properties and concepts in Dutch: a replication of English. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/brkjw/&#34;&gt;https://osf.io/brkjw/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, P., Willems, R. M., &amp;amp; Louwerse, M. M. (2017). Modality switch effects emerge early and increase throughout conceptual processing: Evidence from ERPs. In G. Gunzelmann, A. Howes, T. Tenbrink, &amp;amp; E. J. Davelaar (Eds.), Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society (pp. 1629-1634). Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hauk, O. (2016). Only time will tell—Why temporal information is essential for our neuroscientific understanding of semantics. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 23&lt;/em&gt;, 4, 1072-1079.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockwood, G., Hagoort, P., &amp;amp; Dingemanse, M. (2016). How iconicity helps people learn new words: neural correlates and individual differences in sound-symbolic bootstrapping. &lt;em&gt;Collabra, 2&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Louwerse, M., &amp;amp; Connell, L. (2011). A taste of words: linguistic context and perceptual simulation predict the modality of words. &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Science, 35&lt;/em&gt;, 2, 381-98.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Louwerse, M., &amp;amp; Hutchinson, S. (2012). Neurological evidence linguistic processes precede perceptual simulation in conceptual processing. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology, 3&lt;/em&gt;, 385.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mahon, B. Z., &amp;amp; Caramazza, A. (2008). A critical look at the Embodied Cognition Hypothesis and a new proposal for grounding conceptual content. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Physiology - Paris, 102&lt;/em&gt;, 59-70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scerrati, E., Lugli, L., Nicoletti, R., &amp;amp; Borghi, A. M. (2016). The Multilevel Modality-Switch Effect: What Happens When We See the Bees Buzzing and Hear the Diamonds Glistening. &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review&lt;/em&gt;, doi:10.3758/s13423-016-1150-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vukovic, V., Feurra, M., Shpektor, A., Myachykov, A., &amp;amp; Shtyrov, Y. (2017). Primary motor cortex functionally contributes to language comprehension: An online rTMS study. &lt;em&gt;Neuropsychologia, 96&lt;/em&gt;, 222-229.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modality switch effects emerge early and increase throughout conceptual processing: evidence from ERPs [Dashboard]</title>
      <link>/data-dashboards/bernabeu-etal-2017-modalityswitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/data-dashboards/bernabeu-etal-2017-modalityswitch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href=&#39;https://mybinder.org/v2/gh/pablobernabeu/Modality-switch-effects-emerge-early-and-increase-throughout-conceptual-processing/0a5542658914a6ed01cf8e96252c48bb5bcf8f18?urlpath=shiny/Shiny-app/&#39;&gt;
      &lt;button style = &#34;background-color: white; color: black; border: 2px solid #196F27; border-radius: 12px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h3 style = &#34;margin-top: 7px !important; margin-left: 9px !important; margin-right: 9px !important;&#34;&gt; 
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#DBE6DA;&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-mouse-pointer&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; Dashboard
      &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is from a psychology experiment on the comprehension of words, in which electroencephalographic (EEG) responses were measured. The data are presented in plots spanning 800 milliseconds (the duration of word processing). The aim of this Shiny app is to facilitate the exploration of the data by researchers and the public. Users can delve into the different sections of the data. In a hierarchical order, these sections are groups of participants, individual participants, brain areas, and electrodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shiny apps in science&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By creating this app, I tried to reach beyond the scope of current &lt;em&gt;open science&lt;/em&gt;, which is often confined to files shared on data repositories. I believe that Shiny apps will become general practice in science within a few years (
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.research.lancs.ac.uk/portal/en/activities/presenting-data-interactively-online-using-r-shiny%28c9ce06ac-987e-4141-9121-016f6ee6d16b%29.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;see blog post or slides for more information&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made use of tabs on the top of the dashboard in order to keep the side bar from having too many widgets. I adjusted the appearance of these tabs, and by means of &amp;lsquo;reactivity&amp;rsquo; conditions, also modified the inputs in the sidebar depending on the active tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mainPanel(

	tags$style(HTML(&#39;
	    .tabbable &amp;gt; .nav &amp;gt; li &amp;gt; a                  		{background-color:white; color:#3E454E}
	    .tabbable &amp;gt; .nav &amp;gt; li &amp;gt; a:hover            		{background-color:#002555; color:white}
	    .tabbable &amp;gt; .nav &amp;gt; li[class=active] &amp;gt; a 		{background-color:#ECF4FF; color:black}
	    .tabbable &amp;gt; .nav &amp;gt; li[class=active] &amp;gt; a:hover	{background-color:#E7F1FF; color:black}
	&#39;)),

	tabsetPanel(id=&#39;tabvals&#39;,

            tabPanel(value=1, h4(strong(&#39;Group &amp;amp; Electrode&#39;)), br(), plotOutput(&#39;plot_GroupAndElectrode&#39;),
			h5(a(strong(&#39;See plots with 95% Confidence Intervals&#39;), href=&#39;https://osf.io/2tpxn/&#39;,
			target=&#39;_blank&#39;), style=&#39;text-decoration: underline;&#39;), 
			downloadButton(&#39;downloadPlot.1&#39;, &#39;Download HD plot&#39;), br(), br(),
			# EEG montage
			img(src=&#39;https://preview.ibb.co/n7qiYR/EEG_montage.png&#39;, height=500, width=1000)),

            tabPanel(value=2, h4(strong(&#39;Participant &amp;amp; Area&#39;)), br(), plotOutput(&#39;plot_ParticipantAndLocation&#39;),
			h5(a(strong(&#39;See plots with 95% Confidence Intervals&#39;), href=&#39;https://osf.io/86ch9/&#39;,
			target=&#39;_blank&#39;), style=&#39;text-decoration: underline;&#39;), 
			downloadButton(&#39;downloadPlot.2&#39;, &#39;Download HD plot&#39;), br(), br(),
			# EEG montage
			img(src=&#39;https://preview.ibb.co/n7qiYR/EEG_montage.png&#39;, height=500, width=1000)),

            tabPanel(value=3, h4(strong(&#39;Participant &amp;amp; Electrode&#39;)), br(), plotOutput(&#39;plot_ParticipantAndElectrode&#39;),
			br(), downloadButton(&#39;downloadPlot.3&#39;, &#39;Download HD plot&#39;), br(), br(),
			# EEG montage
			img(src=&#39;https://preview.ibb.co/n7qiYR/EEG_montage.png&#39;, height=500, width=1000)),

            tabPanel(value=4, h4(strong(&#39;OLD Group &amp;amp; Electrode&#39;)), br(), plotOutput(&#39;plot_OLDGroupAndElectrode&#39;),
			h5(a(strong(&#39;See plots with 95% Confidence Intervals&#39;), href=&#39;https://osf.io/dvs2z/&#39;,
			target=&#39;_blank&#39;), style=&#39;text-decoration: underline;&#39;), 
			downloadButton(&#39;downloadPlot.4&#39;, &#39;Download HD plot&#39;), br(), br(),
			# EEG montage
			img(src=&#39;https://preview.ibb.co/n7qiYR/EEG_montage.png&#39;, height=500, width=1000))
	),
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data set was fairly large, considering the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s hosted with the free plan. In order to lighten the processing, I split the data into various files, reducing the total size. Furthermore, I outsourced a particularly heavy set of plots (those with Confidence Intervals) to PDF files, to which I linked in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;h5(a(strong(&#39;See plots with 95% Confidence Intervals&#39;), href=&#39;https://osf.io/dvs2z/&#39;,
			target=&#39;_blank&#39;), style=&#39;text-decoration: underline;&#39;),
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also used web links to the published paper and raw data, as well as to the &lt;em&gt;server&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ui&lt;/em&gt; scripts. These files, along with the data, are publicly available 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/97unm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;in this repository&lt;/a&gt;; they may be accessed within the &amp;ldquo;Files&amp;rdquo; section, by opening the folders &amp;ldquo;ERPs&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Analyses of ERPs averaged across trials&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Shiny app&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another feature I added was the download button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# From server.R script

spec_title = paste0(&#39;ERP waveforms for &#39;, input$var.Group, &#39; Group, Electrode &#39;, input$var.Electrodes.1, &#39; (negative values upward; time windows displayed)&#39;)

plot_GroupAndElectrode = ggplot(df2, aes(x=time, y=-microvolts, color=condition)) +
  geom_rect(xmin=160, xmax=216, ymin=7.5, ymax=-8, color = &#39;grey75&#39;, fill=&#39;black&#39;, alpha=0, linetype=&#39;longdash&#39;) +
  geom_rect(xmin=270, xmax=370, ymin=7.5, ymax=-8, color = &#39;grey75&#39;, fill=&#39;black&#39;, alpha=0, linetype=&#39;longdash&#39;) +
  geom_rect(xmin=350, xmax=550, ymin=8, ymax=-7.5, color = &#39;grey75&#39;, fill=&#39;black&#39;, alpha=0, linetype=&#39;longdash&#39;) +
  geom_rect(xmin=500, xmax=750, ymin=7.5, ymax=-8, color = &#39;grey75&#39;, fill=&#39;black&#39;, alpha=0, linetype=&#39;longdash&#39;) +
  geom_line(size=1, alpha = 1) + scale_linetype_manual(values=colours) +
  scale_y_continuous(limits=c(-8.38, 8.3), breaks=seq(-8,8,by=1), expand = c(0,0.1)) +
  scale_x_continuous(limits=c(-208,808),breaks=seq(-200,800,by=100), expand = c(0.005,0), labels= c(&#39;-200&#39;,&#39;-100 ms&#39;,&#39;0&#39;,&#39;100 ms&#39;,&#39;200&#39;,&#39;300 ms&#39;,&#39;400&#39;,&#39;500 ms&#39;,&#39;600&#39;,&#39;700 ms&#39;,&#39;800&#39;)) +
  ggtitle(spec_title) + theme_bw() + geom_vline(xintercept=0) +
  annotate(geom=&#39;segment&#39;, y=seq(-8,8,1), yend=seq(-8,8,1), x=-4, xend=8, color=&#39;black&#39;) +
  annotate(geom=&#39;segment&#39;, y=-8.2, yend=-8.38, x=seq(-200,800,100), xend=seq(-200,800,100), color=&#39;black&#39;) +
  geom_segment(x = -200, y = 0, xend = 800, yend = 0, size=0.5, color=&#39;black&#39;) +
  theme(legend.position = c(0.100, 0.150), legend.background = element_rect(fill=&#39;#EEEEEE&#39;, size=0),
	axis.title=element_blank(), legend.key.width = unit(1.2,&#39;cm&#39;), legend.text=element_text(size=17),
	legend.title = element_text(size=17, face=&#39;bold&#39;), plot.title= element_text(size=20, hjust = 0.5, vjust=2),
	axis.text.y = element_blank(), axis.text.x = element_text(size = 14, vjust= 2.12, face=&#39;bold&#39;, color = &#39;grey32&#39;, family=&#39;sans&#39;),
	axis.ticks=element_blank(), panel.border = element_blank(), panel.grid.major = element_blank(), 
	panel.grid.minor = element_blank(), plot.margin = unit(c(0.1,0.1,0,0), &#39;cm&#39;)) +
  annotate(&#39;segment&#39;, x=160, xend=216, y=-8, yend=-8, colour = &#39;grey75&#39;, size = 1.5) +
  annotate(&#39;segment&#39;, x=270, xend=370, y=-8, yend=-8, colour = &#39;grey75&#39;, size = 1.5) +
  annotate(&#39;segment&#39;, x=350, xend=550, y=-7.5, yend=-7.5, colour = &#39;grey75&#39;, size = 1.5) +
  annotate(&#39;segment&#39;, x=500, xend=750, y=-8, yend=-8, colour = &#39;grey75&#39;, size = 1.5) +
  scale_fill_manual(name = &#39;Context / Target trial&#39;, values=colours) +
  scale_color_manual(name = &#39;Context / Target trial&#39;, values=colours) +
  guides(linetype=guide_legend(override.aes = list(size=1.2))) +
   guides(color=guide_legend(override.aes = list(size=2.5))) +
# Print y axis labels within plot area:
  annotate(&#39;text&#39;, label = expression(bold(&#39;\u2013&#39; * &#39;3 &#39; * &#39;\u03bc&#39; * &#39;V&#39;)), x = -29, y = 3, size = 4.5, color = &#39;grey32&#39;, family=&#39;sans&#39;) +
  annotate(&#39;text&#39;, label = expression(bold(&#39;+3 &#39; * &#39;\u03bc&#39; * &#39;V&#39;)), x = -29, y = -3, size = 4.5, color = &#39;grey32&#39;, family=&#39;sans&#39;) +
  annotate(&#39;text&#39;, label = expression(bold(&#39;\u2013&#39; * &#39;6 &#39; * &#39;\u03bc&#39; * &#39;V&#39;)), x = -29, y = 6, size = 4.5, color = &#39;grey32&#39;, family=&#39;sans&#39;)

print(plot_GroupAndElectrode)

output$downloadPlot.1 &amp;lt;- downloadHandler(
	filename &amp;lt;- function(file){
	paste0(input$var.Group, &#39; group, electrode &#39;, input$var.Electrodes.1, &#39;, &#39;, Sys.Date(), &#39;.png&#39;)},
   	content &amp;lt;- function(file){
      		png(file, units=&#39;in&#39;, width=13, height=5, res=900)
      		print(plot_GroupAndElectrode)
      		dev.off()},
	contentType = &#39;image/png&#39;)
  } )
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# From ui.R script

downloadButton(&#39;downloadPlot.1&#39;, &#39;Download HD plot&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rising to the challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience with Shiny has been so good I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2017/01/01/the-case-for-data-dashboards.-first-steps-with-r-shiny/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;my experience&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, on my first crawling days, I spent an eternity stuck with this elephant in my room: &amp;ldquo;μ&amp;rdquo;. This &lt;em&gt;μ&lt;/em&gt; letter (micro-souvenir from hell, as I later knew it), was part of the labels of my plots. All I knew was that I could not deploy the app online, even while I could perfectly launch it locally in my laptop. So, I wondered what use was to deploy locally if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t publish the app?! Eventually, I read about UTF-8 encoding in one forum. Bless them forums. All I had to do was use &amp;ldquo;Âμ&amp;rdquo; instead of the single &amp;ldquo;μ&amp;rdquo;. A better option I found later was: &lt;code&gt;expression(&amp;quot;\u03bc&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond encoding issues, I had a tough time embedding images. You know, the &amp;lsquo;www&amp;rsquo; folder&amp;hellip; To be honest, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t handled the &amp;lsquo;www&amp;rsquo; way&amp;ndash;but where there&amp;rsquo;s a will there&amp;rsquo;s a way. I managed to include my images by uploading them to a website and then entering their URL in &amp;ldquo;img(src&amp;rdquo;, avoiding the use of folder paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img(src=&amp;quot;https://preview.ibb.co/n7qiYR/EEG_montage.png 1&amp;quot;, height=500, width=1000)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long after I had built the app, I added another image&amp;ndash;the &lt;em&gt;favicon&lt;/em&gt; (the little icon on the browser tab).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;tags$head(tags$link(rel=&amp;quot;shortcut icon&amp;quot;, href=&amp;quot;https://image.ibb.co/fXUwzb/favic.png&amp;quot;)),  # web favicon
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style = &#34;text-indent:-2em; margin-left:2em;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, P., Willems, R. M., &amp;amp; Louwerse, M. M. (2017). Modality switch effects emerge early and increase throughout conceptual processing: Evidence from ERPs [Data dashboard]. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pablobernabeu.shinyapps.io/ERP-waveform-visualization_CMS-experiment/&#34;&gt;https://pablobernabeu.shinyapps.io/ERP-waveform-visualization_CMS-experiment/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modality switch effects emerge early and increase throughout conceptual processing: evidence from ERPs [Paper]</title>
      <link>/publication/bernabeu-etal-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/bernabeu-etal-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;bonus-a-conference-poster-with-further-analyses-nbspa-hrefhttpsmfrosfiorenderurlhttpsosfiodj52ndirect26moderender26actiondownload26moderenderi-classfas-fa-external-link-altia&#34;&gt;Bonus: a conference poster with further analyses  &lt;a href=&#39;https://mfr.osf.io/render?url=https://osf.io/dj52n/?direct%26mode=render%26action=download%26mode=render&#39;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-external-link-alt&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;style&gt;.embed-responsive{position:relative;height:100%;}.embed-responsive iframe{position:absolute;height:100%;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;script&gt;window.jQuery || document.write(&#39;&lt;script src=&#34;//code.jquery.com/jquery-1.11.2.min.js&#34;&gt;\x3C/script&gt;&#39;) &lt;/script&gt;&lt;link href=&#34;https://mfr.osf.io/static/css/mfr.css&#34; media=&#34;all&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34;&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;mfrIframe&#34; class=&#34;mfr mfr-file&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://mfr.osf.io/static/js/mfr.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;script&gt;var mfrRender = new mfr.Render(&#34;mfrIframe&#34;, &#34;https://mfr.osf.io/render?url=https://osf.io/dj52n/?direct%26mode=render%26action=download%26mode=render&#34;);&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style = &#34;text-indent:-2em; margin-left:2em;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernabeu, P., Willems, R. M., &amp;amp; Louwerse, M. M. (2017). Modality switch effects emerge early and increase throughout conceptual processing: Evidence from ERPs. In G. Gunzelmann, A. Howes, T. Tenbrink, &amp;amp; E. J. Davelaar (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1629-1634). Austin, TX: Cognitive Science Society. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindmodeling.org/cogsci2017/papers/0318/&#34;&gt;https://mindmodeling.org/cogsci2017/papers/0318/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
