<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open materials | Pablo Bernabeu</title>
    <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/open-materials/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/open-materials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>open materials</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Pablo Bernabeu, 2015—2026. Licence: [CC BY 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/). Email: pcbernabeu@gmail.com. Cookies only used by third-party systems such as [Disqus](https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717155-use-of-cookies).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/img/default_preview_image.png</url>
      <title>open materials</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/tags/open-materials/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the paper: Why open science is the new research standard</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2026/open-science-new-research-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2026/open-science-new-research-standard/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Scientific research is undergoing a fundamental transformation, born from a decade of introspection and a growing demand for integrity. What began as a response to the ‘replication crisis’ has evolved from a niche advocacy movement into a global standard for excellence. We are moving away from a ‘trust me’ culture, where findings were taken on faith, toward a ‘show me’ culture where transparency is the primary currency of credibility. This momentum is now irreversible, as underscored by recent publications from leading journals and platforms like &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Conversation&lt;/em&gt;, including ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-023-01790-z&#34;&gt;Trust but verify&lt;/a&gt;’, ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54614-2&#34;&gt;Reproducibility and transparency: What’s going on and how can we help&lt;/a&gt;’ and ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/reproducibility-may-be-the-key-idea-students-need-to-balance-trust-in-evidence-with-healthy-skepticism-251771&#34;&gt;Reproducibility may be the key idea students need to balance trust in evidence with healthy scepticism&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-mechanics-of-transparency&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Mechanics of Transparency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open science is more than a philosophy; it is a practical toolkit for robust research. At its heart are two pillars: preregistration and the open sharing of data and materials. Preregistration involves publicly archiving the theoretical background, research methods and hypotheses before data collection begins. This simple act serves as a powerful antidote to questionable research practices like ‘p-hacking’ (tweaking analyses to find a significant result) and ‘HARKing’ (hypothesising after results are known). It draws a clear line between planned confirmatory research and exploratory discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This transparent approach creates a beneficial scenario for everyone in the research ecosystem. For funders, it maximises their return on investment, as open science ensures that funding continues to yield dividends long after the final report is filed. By sharing data under a licence such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/legalcode.en&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International Public Licence (CC BY-NC-ND 4.0)&lt;/a&gt;—the gold standard for protecting intellectual credit while preventing unauthorised commercial use—funders demonstrate a commitment to cutting-edge corporate social responsibility. There are many possible licences with varying permissions and restrictions; for instance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode.en&#34;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt; allows all use provided an acknowledgement of authorship. Funders can also be prominently featured in OSF repositories with direct links that help document their role in high-quality, reproducible research for a global audience, as shown in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/fajne&#34;&gt;example repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the project itself, adopting these protocols provides prestige through rigour. It distinguishes the work from the ‘black box’ approach of traditional studies, and signals to peer reviewers and international collaborators that the study is a gold-standard project, positioned at the vanguard of modern academic practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For researchers, especially those in the early stages of their careers, open science is a strategic move. Sharing data and code on platforms like the Open Science Framework (OSF) creates a public, citable portfolio of technical expertise. This demonstrates a capacity for meticulous, transparent work and facilitates recognition and collaboration far beyond a standard CV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the wider scientific community, the true power of open science lies in its ability to accelerate discovery. By providing a unique, high-quality dataset and analysis framework, we allow others to independently verify our findings, which strengthens the overall body of knowledge, and to repurpose data for new research questions, which multiplies the impact of the original funding and fosters innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;a-commitment-to-integrity&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Commitment to Integrity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open science is not an ‘optional extra’ or a bureaucratic hurdle; it is a commitment to the idea that the best science is done in the light. By prioritising transparency, we ensure that our findings are not just published but permanent, verifiable and truly impactful. In an era of misinformation, this commitment to demonstrable truth is more critical than ever. As we move forward, these practices will define which projects lead the conversation and which are left behind in the archives. The goal is simple: to produce research that is not just ‘right for now’ but remains robust, reusable and trustworthy for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the paper: Why open science is the new research standard</title>
      <link>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2025/motivating-open-science-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pablobernabeu.github.io/2025/motivating-open-science-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific research is undergoing a fundamental transformation. What began in the early 2010s as a niche advocacy movement has evolved into a global standard for excellence. We are moving away from a &amp;lsquo;trust me&amp;rsquo; culture toward a &amp;lsquo;show me&amp;rsquo; culture, where transparency is the primary currency of credibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following recent publications from Nature and The Conversation underscore why this momentum is now irreversible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-023-01790-z&#34;&gt;Trust but verify&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;Nature Materials&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54614-2&#34;&gt;Reproducibility and transparency: What’s going on and how can we help&lt;/a&gt; – Nature Communications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/reproducibility-may-be-the-key-idea-students-need-to-balance-trust-in-evidence-with-healthy-skepticism-251771&#34;&gt;Reproducibility may be the key idea students need to balance trust in evidence with healthy skepticism&lt;/a&gt; – The Conversation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-mechanics-of-transparency&#34;&gt;The Mechanics of Transparency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open science is more than a philosophy; it is a practical toolkit. At the heart of our methodology are two pillars: preregistration (the public archiving of the theoretical background, the research methods to be used and hypotheses posited before data collection) and the open sharing of raw data and materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach creates a &amp;lsquo;win-win-win-win&amp;rsquo; scenario for everyone involved in the research ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Funders: Maximising Research ROI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open science ensures that a funder’s investment continues to yield dividends long after the final report is filed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lasting Visibility: By sharing data under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/legalcode.en&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International Public License (abbreviated as CC BY-NC-ND 4.0)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;the gold standard for protecting intellectual credit while preventing unauthorised commercial use&amp;mdash;funders demonstrate a commitment to cutting-edge corporate social responsibility (e.g., see &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/search?filter_rights=%5B%7B%22label%22:%22CC-By%20Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives%204.0%20International%22,%22value%22:%22https:%2F%2Fcreativecommons.org%2Flicenses%2Fby-nc-nd%2F4.0%2Flegalcode%22,%22cardSearchResultCount%22:19302%7D%5D&#34;&gt;OSF projects using this licence&lt;/a&gt;). There are lots of possible licences with varying permissions and restrictions. For instance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode.en&#34;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt; allows all use provided an acknowledgment of the authorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public Recognition: Funders can be prominently featured in OSF repositories using direct links that help document the funder&#39;s role in high-quality, reproducible research for a global audience (see an &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/fajne&#34;&gt;example repository&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Project: Prestige through Rigour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By adopting these protocols, a project distinguishes itself from the &amp;lsquo;black box&amp;rsquo; approach of traditional studies. It signals to peer reviewers and international collaborators that the study is a gold-standard project, positioned at the vanguard of modern academic practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Researchers: Building a Living Portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the research team, especially early-career researchers (ECRs), open science is a strategic career move. Sharing data on the Open Science Framework (OSF) creates a public, citable portfolio of technical expertise, facilitating recognition and collaboration far beyond a standard CV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Community: The Multiplier Effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true power of open science lies in its ability to empower others. By providing a unique, high-quality dataset and analysis framework, we allow the global scientific community to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independently verify our findings, strengthening the overall body of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repurpose data for new research questions, multiplying the impact of the original funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-commitment-to-integrity&#34;&gt;A Commitment to Integrity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open science is not an &amp;lsquo;optional extra&amp;rsquo; or a bureaucratic hurdle; it is a commitment to the idea that the best science is done in the light. By prioritising transparency, we ensure that our findings are not just published, but permanent, verifiable and truly impactful. As we move forward, these practices will define which projects lead the conversation and which are left behind in the archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The goal is simple:&lt;/strong&gt; To produce research that isn&#39;t just &amp;lsquo;right for now,&amp;rsquo; but remains robust and reusable for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
